the number one reason for breakups is
导致分手的首要原因
not Finance infidelity it's if you do
并非经济或不忠，而是如果你选择经济或不忠，那么
that there's a 99% likelihood who break
分手的可能性高达99%。
up that's pretty crazy when you think
想想都觉得不可思议。
about it Paul Carrick Brunson the
保罗·卡里克·布伦森，
world's most influential Matchmaker you
世界上最具影响力的媒人，指出如果你
choose a weak partner not only do you
选择一个软弱的伴侣，你不仅寿命更
not live as long not as happy more
短、更不幸福、更
unhealthy but you could literally suffer
不健康，甚至可能面临
death so who you choose as the most
死亡。所以，选择伴侣是你人生中最
important decision you could make so I
重要的决定。我
have questions you ready for this
有一些问题，准备好了吗？约会
what is the state of dating it's a hell
现状如何？这真是个
of a problem how do you spot a
棘手的问题。如何识别
narcissist so the key is to this golden
自恋者？关键在于
mean thing in your book what is that
你书中提到的“黄金分割”概念。
it's the optimal measure of what we
它指的是衡量
consider to be sexy poor women is the
女性性感身材的最佳标准——
percentage of your waist to your hips so
腰臀比。那么，
what is the future of dating I know a
约会的未来会怎样？我知道
lot of people would be mad at me for
很多人会因此对我生气，
this but you go there if you want to
但如果你想深入探讨，那就去看看吧。就像
it's like arrange marriages data shows
包办婚姻一样，数据显示，
us people in the range marriage have
自由恋爱的人对婚姻的
higher satisfaction because and this is
满意度更高，而这
often where many people go wrong what
往往是许多人犯错的地方。
should I be looking for in a partner it
我应该在伴侣身上寻找什么？
has come at 10 years of research on this
这方面的研究已经持续了10年。
there's five key characteristics that we
我们需要五个关键特征。
one Paul I wanted to go over this thing
保罗，我想谈谈
called attachment Theory because I think
依恋理论，因为我觉得
I'm in avoidant attachment style I love
我是回避型依恋。我很喜欢
this topic there's some phenomenal
这个话题。有一些非常棒的
research looking at the number of
研究，探讨了
orgasms that people have based on their
人们的性高潮次数与
attachment style and if they were
依恋类型之间的关系，
avoidant the data showed that no comment
数据显示，如果是回避型依恋，性高潮次数会更少。好了，言归正传。
Moving on but I have to say why though
不过，我必须说说为什么
this is important
这件事很重要。首先，
quick one this is really really
这件事真的让
fascinating to me on the back end of our
我很着迷。在我们
YouTube channel it says that
YouTube频道的后台，数据显示，在我们
channel haven't yet hit the Subscribe
频道开播以来，经常观看我们频道的观众中有69.9%还没有点击订阅
button I just wanted to ask you a favor
按钮。我只是想请你们帮个忙。
it helps this channel so much if you
如果您选择订阅，这对我们频道的帮助非常大，可以帮助
guest helps us scale the production and
我们扩大嘉宾阵容，提升制作水平，让
it makes the show bigger so if I could
节目更精彩。所以，
ask you for one favor if you've watched
如果您
the show before and you've enjoyed it
之前看过我们的节目，并且喜欢它，
and you like this episode that you're
也喜欢您正在观看的这一集，
currently watching could you please hit
请您点击
the Subscribe button thank you so much
订阅按钮。非常感谢！为了回报您的支持，
and I will pay that gesture by making
我会确保我们在
sure that everything we do here gets
这里所做的一切都越来越
better and better and better and better
好，越来越好，越来越好。这是
that is a promise I'm willing to make
我向您做出的承诺。
PA last time I had you on my show you
上次你上我的节目时，你
were a Smash Hit And I look at the
可是大受欢迎。我回顾之前的
episodes and I can see the retention of
节目，发现
every conversation I have the retention
每次对话的收听率都很高。收听率指的是
conversation someone listened to you and
听众听了你谈话的时长，而
you're a really
你绝对是
record breaker on our show in terms of
我们节目收听率的纪录保持者，
retention because the message that you
因为你传递的信息非常引人入胜，而且很容易引起共鸣。
compelling relatable way but you're
你
speaking to a problem that all of us
谈到的是我们每个人
have in our lives which is this problem
生活中都会遇到的问题——
of love yes and just I I know your story
爱情问题。我知道你的故事，
but there's there's a chance that some
但可能有些
people that that have just clicked this
刚点开这个节目的人
don't know your
并不了解你的
story the wisdom you have what is the
故事。你拥有怎样的智慧？
experience that you've been on and how
你有哪些经验？这些经验持续了
long is that experience and what's the
多久？你积累了哪些
experience that has culminated in this
经验，才最终形成了
wisdom you have about relationship
你对人际关系
science what have you been exposed to
科学的深刻理解？你接触过哪些领域？接触了
and how long for I spent my first part
多久？我职业
of my career in finance so I was a
生涯的早期是在金融领域，我曾是
researcher in Investment Banking I went
投资银行的研究员，后来
off got my business degree you know so I
拿到了商科学位。我当时走的是
I was on that track and then I switched
这条路，后来我转而
the track to focus on relationship
专注于人际关系领域。 我最初从事
science and then in the process of
科学研究，后来在
switching I had an opportunity to work
转型过程中，我有幸为
for two incredible people two
两位杰出人士——两位
billionaires so in the Rel on the
亿万富翁——工作。在
finance side it was a gentleman by the
金融领域，我曾为一位
name of Enver Yugo who's a billionaire
名叫恩维尔·尤戈的
out of turkey and owns the largest
土耳其亿万富翁工作，他拥有世界上最大的
for-profit education company in the
营利性教育公司。
world and then when I switched into
之后，当我转行到
relationship science I had an
人际关系科学领域时，我又有
opportunity of working for Oprah Winfrey
机会为奥普拉·温弗瑞工作。
right and so these were two billionaires
这两位都是亿万富翁，
and I say billionaires I underscore that
我特意强调“亿万富翁”，
because they were two entirely different
因为他们
people different characteristics
性格迥异，
different uh setups at home but yet they
家庭环境也截然不同，但他们的
had the same behaviors and I started to
行为却有相似之处。我开始
write about those behavor behaviors and
研究这些行为，并
by writing about those behaviors I ended
最终通过写作
up becoming a journalist for USA Today
成为《今日美国》的记者。
my wife and I launched what was
我和妻子创办了当时
business in the United States and then
美国最大的婚介公司，并
we sold that in 2017 and that's what
在2017年将其出售。正是这笔交易
ended up allowing us to come to the UK
让我们得以来到英国。
but the heart of what I do is I I'm the
但我工作的核心在于，我是
relationship science I I wake up every
人际关系科学领域最大的书呆子，我每天
morning I'm reading some bit of research
早上醒来都会阅读一些相关的研究。
I'm going to sleep every night falling
我每晚都会一边听着
asleep uh on some lecture around around
关于
relationship science I I think it's it's
人际关系科学的讲座一边入睡。我认为这是
one of the most
最
undervalued areas and the decisions that
被低估的领域之一，
we make around relationships are have
我们在人际关系方面做出的决定会对我们的
up what happens in our lives what
人生走向、我们
happens to the lives of those around us
身边人的生活
and what happens to the Lives who come
以及我们
after us our children so these are very
后代（我们的孩子）的生活产生巨大的影响。所以这些都是非常
important decisions and I think that's
重要的决定，我想这就是为什么
the reason why it occupies so much of my
它占据了我如此多的
thought have you been exposed to any
思考。你接触过任何
first party data I know that you I think
第一方数据吗？我知道你，我想
maybe was it Tinder have shown you some
可能是Tinder给你看过一些
data yeah absolutely last year I became
数据吧？是的，当然。去年我成为了
the head of global insights for Tinder
Tinder的全球洞察主管，这让
and what that has allowed me to do is
我能够
see quite honestly more data on dating
看到更多关于约会的数据，坦白说，这些数据让
that gives me more insight than I think
我比
I'd say a lot of people in the world uh
世界上很多人都更了解约会。
i h i co-wrote a a report this year
今年我与人合著了一份名为《2023年约会的未来》的报告，这份报告
looks at behavior on the app and also
分析了Tinder应用上的行为以及
Behavior around the world and I made
全球范围内的行为，我在报告中做出了
some projections in there j z is going
一些预测，比如未来将会
to have the
拥有史上最牢固的
strongest strong the strongest marriages
婚姻。
ever which which a lot of look see face
很多人看了之后都一脸懵，
everyone's like what yeah so so I made
好像在说“什么？是啊，所以我做了
some bold predictions in there um but uh
一些大胆的预测”。嗯，但是，但是，但是，
but but but but absolutely T Tinder that
但是，绝对的，Tinder 的
partnership has allowed me some great
合作让我对
insights what is the state of dating
约会的现状和未来有了很多深刻的见解。
view I want to know like where we are as
我想知道，作为一个
a as a people and also I guess
群体，我们身处何方。而且，我想，要
understanding where we are we have to
了解我们身处何方，我们必须
understand where we've come from and
了解我们从何而来，
then from there we can understand where
然后才能了解
we're going I guess yes yeah let's look
我们将走向何方。我想是的，让我们回顾一下。
back okay so we you know humans 300,000
好的，你知道，人类大约在 30 万
years ago right started there was no
年前出现，那时还没有
dating it was more so what was called
约会，更多的是一种叫做
assortative mating which was the
同型交配的现象，即
selection of other people based on
根据
similar characteristics so we would look
相似特征选择伴侣。我们会观察
at someone and say okay you behave
某人，然后说：“好吧，你的行为和我
similar to how I behave you look kind of
相似，你的外貌也和我相似，
like how I look therefore we will mate
所以我们会交配。” 而最终
and the whole objective was procreation
目的就是繁衍后代。这就是
that was it in hunter gatherer days and
狩猎采集时代的情况，这种现象一直延续
you could take that all the way up into
到
1800s so Eli finle is a great researcher
19 世纪。伊莱·芬勒是一位
out of New York and he wrote one of my
来自纽约的杰出研究员，他写了一本我
favorite books the all Oro marriage and
最喜欢的书。 奥罗
he calls that entire phase the pragmatic
称婚姻的整个阶段为务实
phase you were making a a a selection
阶段，你选择伴侣是
based on the fact that you wanted to
基于你想
live next week right that that was that
活到下周的事实，对吧？这就是
was why you chose a partner or or the
你选择伴侣或
procreation of it but then between the
生育的原因。但从
1800s and the 1960s is what Eli fle
19世纪到20世纪60年代，埃利·弗莱
calls the Romantic Period this is the
称之为浪漫时期。在这个
period where we began to say okay hold
时期，我们开始意识到
on for a second the Industrial
工业
Revolution is happening we're moving
革命正在发生，我们正走向
into more nuclear fam so we're moving
更核心的家庭模式，所以我们正在
away from our Clans if you will and
远离家族，
therefore I'm lonely I don't have my
因此我感到孤独，我的
cousins around me anymore I'm working in
表兄弟姐妹都不在我身边了，我
this job all day this Factory all day so
整天在工厂里工作，所以我
this partner of mine who formerly was
的伴侣，以前
all about pretty much just my sex
几乎只是我的性伴侣，
partner now is going to become my friend
现在将成为我的朋友。在
so this romantic age is where you see
这个浪漫时期，你会看到
companionship rise but still in that
陪伴的增加，但即使在这个
phase you're still not receiving all of
阶段，你仍然无法获得
your value all of all of what you love
你全部的价值，你爱
about a partner is not coming from just
伴侣的所有东西并非都来自
the partner or should I say all of what
伴侣，或者应该说，
you need in life is not coming from your
你生活中所有需要的东西并非都来自你的
partner your intellectual stimulation is
伴侣，你的精神刺激可能
coming from someone down the street
来自街坊邻居，对吧？
right you have friends at work that you
你在工作中会和朋友一起玩乐，享受
use For Your Entertainment and joy but
快乐，但
your partner is beginning to become your
你的伴侣开始成为你的
companion and that's the second phase
伴侣，这就是第二阶段，对吧？
right that that's the second phase is
第二阶段是
the Romantic phase and then in 1960 what
浪漫阶段。到了1960年，在
you see happening and this is in Western
西方
Society is you see what the pill is
社会，你会看到避孕药被
created you see the uh the the the the
发明出来，
the washing machine is created and these
洗衣机也被发明出来，
inst these these tools if you will begin
这些工具开始
to free women right we're still living
解放女性。没错，我们仍然生活
in a patriarchy hands down but in the
在一个父权制社会中，但在
1960s you began to see women For the
20世纪60年代，你开始看到女性
First Time begin to have a little bit of
第一次在选择伴侣方面拥有一些
decision a little bit of choice in who
决定权和选择权。
they chose as a partner and from the
从20世纪60年代开始，我们进入了
1960s on you have what Eli fle calls the
伊莱·弗莱所说的“
self-expression now the reason why this
自我表达时代”。这
is so important for us today is because
对我们今天如此重要的原因在于，
what ends up happening is now you move
最终的结果是，当我们
forward to today what do we want well we
展望今天时，我们想要什么？我们
want the highest level of well-being as
想要最高水平的幸福感，正如
maslo would say you think about maso's
马斯洛所说。想想马斯洛的
hierarchy of needs at the bottom is you
需求层次理论，最底层是
just want food you just want shelter you
食物、住所和
just want to be safe but as you get
安全，但随着…… 获得
those things you go higher and higher to
这些东西，你就会不断攀登
the pyramid and the top of the pyramid
金字塔，而金字塔的顶端
is
是
self-actualization and this is what most
自我实现。这正是
of us want because most of us are living
我们大多数人想要的，因为我们大多数人都生活
in a state of privilege we have water we
在优越的环境中——我们有水、
have food we have shelter so we want to
有食物、有住所。所以我们想要
be our best selves we want to flourish
成为最好的自己，想要蓬勃发展。
as Aristotle said we want to flourish so
正如亚里士多德所说，我们想要蓬勃发展。
if we want to flourish now then we need
如果我们想要蓬勃发展，那么我们需要
a partner who can help us flourish it's
一个能够帮助我们蓬勃发展的伴侣。这
no longer about the 1800s or the 1,000
不再是19世纪或1000年代那种
where you just needed a partner to to
需要伴侣仅仅是为了发生
you know basically have sex with and
性关系，并
make sure they could you know protect
确保他们能够保护
you like we we're gone from that we now
我们的方式了。我们已经超越了那种模式，现在
we want
我们想要
self-expression and if we want
自我表达。如果我们想要
self-expression we have different Di BS
自我表达，我们就需要
on our partner and that means dating is
对伴侣有不同的要求。这意味着
now more complicated than it has ever
现在的约会比以往任何时候都更加复杂。
been everybody thinks they want Choice
每个人都认为自己想要选择，无论
men and women we all think we want
男女，我们都认为自己想要
choice but I I'm quite fascinated by the
选择。但我对
psychology of choice and how it can
选择的心理学非常着迷，它会导致
result in indecision but also valuing
优柔寡断，也会影响人们对所
what you've chosen less or more and
选择之物的重视程度，
that's sort of context dependent I think
我认为这在某种程度上取决于具体情况。
here about arranged marriages and you
你
talk about that in the book and what we
在书中谈到了包办婚姻，以及我们
can learn from arranged marriages
可以从中学到什么。你知道，在包办婚姻中，
where you're given very little Choice
你几乎没有任何选择余地。是的，那么会
yes yeah so what happens there yeah this
发生什么呢？这
is a controversial one in in the book
在书中是一个颇具争议的话题，
and I I know a lot of people are going
我知道很多人会因此对
be mad at me for this but here's what
我生气，但
the data tells us that arranged
数据显示，包办
marriages on average last longer and
婚姻平均而言持续时间更长，而且
both and both people in the arranged
包办
marriage have higher
婚姻中的双方都更
satisfaction now I will also say a lot
满意。当然，我也要指出，很多
of people are entering arranged
人在没有任何选择的情况下就步入了包办
marriages with no decision a lot of
婚姻。很多
arranged marriages um are happening
包办婚姻，
where I would say are amoral right
我认为，在道德上是不道德的。
however let's look at why it could be
然而，让我们来看看原因。
because I think that's the beauty of
我认为，这就是实证
empirical evidence of research is it
研究的魅力所在：它
allows you to think about the
能让你思考各种
possibility of why and what what can we
可能性，以及我们能从
learn from this one of the reasons why
中学到什么。其中一个原因是，
is because when we think we're in love
当我们以为自己恋爱时，我们
most of us are not most most of us are
大多数人其实并非如此。我们大多数人只是处于一种
in this blind state of limerance where
盲目的迷恋状态，
we are infatuated with the person in
我们被眼前的人深深吸引，却对
about them and we know nothing about
他们一无所知，也不懂如何做
decision-making and we don't fully trust
决定。 不要完全信任
them the sex is good right and we say
他们，性生活很和谐，对吧？然后我们就会说，
Okay I want to spend the rest of my life
好吧，我想
with this person right what's happening
和这个人共度余生。
in most arranged marriages is you have a
大多数包办婚姻中，你身边会有一个“
village you have multiple people in your
村庄”，你身边有很多关心你的人，
sphere could be parents brothers sisters
可能是父母、兄弟姐妹、
friends who have your best interest and
朋友等等，他们都会为你着想。他们会
they sit and they cohesively decide is
坐下来，共同决定
this the right partner for you and
这个人是否适合你。
they're looking at behaviors that you
他们会观察一些
may not be able to see you know I saw
你可能看不到的行为。我在
this with my matchmaking agency in the
我的婚介机构就遇到过这种情况。在我的
matchmaking agency the first thing that
婚介机构里，当
we would do when a client would come in
客户来的时候，我们做的第一件事就是
interview friends and family co-workers
采访他的朋友、家人、同事、上级、下级、
people who report to you previous
前
girlfriends you know love interests and
女友，以及你曾经的恋爱对象。我会通过这些访谈来
with that I would look for the consensus
寻找共识，
and and I would I would use all of that
然后我会利用所有这些信息
to say okay this is who step is he comes
来判断：好吧，这就是这个人。他来的时候
in and he tells me this is who he is but
告诉我他是这样的，但
I talk to all of these people in his
我跟他
sphere and I understand this is who he
身边的所有人谈过之后，我了解到他其实是这样的。
is and the reason why we have a hard
我们很难真正
time understanding who we are is because
了解自己，是因为
of cognitive dissonance right we believe
认知失调。我们
as human beings we think that we behave
作为人类，总是认为自己的行为和
as we think we behave but we actually
想法一致。 我们表面上表现得好像很懂事，但实际上我们并不喜欢我们口口声声说重视的东西。
value chances are we don't really value
我们可能并不真正重视那些东西。你知道，
that you know in matchmaking again I
在婚介中，我
would ask what are your values and then
会问对方的价值观是什么，然后
they would give me this long list oh you
他们会列出一长串清单，比如“
know I'm I'm a Christian uh and I uh
我是基督徒，我
Value Health and right so this is what
重视健康”。好吧，这就是
you do and then two days later I'd say
你平时做的事。两天后，我会问：“
okay last Saturday when you were off
上周六你
work what did you do with your time oh I
休息的时候都做了些什么？”他们会说：“我
went out and I pigged out I ate all day
出去大吃大喝了，吃了一整天，
and then I went to this concert and I
然后去看了场演唱会，还做了其他事。”然后我会
did this and I said well where was
问：“那去
church in that where was Bible study
教堂了吗？去参加圣经学习了吗？
where was this and what I've noticed is
这些事呢？”我注意到，
that where we spend that free time where
我们如何支配空闲时间，如何支配
we spend our discretionary
可支配收入，
money that's what we value so true I've
这才是我们真正重视的东西。确实如此。我
thought a lot about this recently about
最近一直在思考这个问题，
how what I say should be reflected in
我所说的话应该如何体现在
how my calendar looks yes and that is
我的日程安排上。是的，这才是
the true sort of evidence of me living
真正体现我践行
my values and really what I do value and
价值观和真正重视的东西的证据。
I think people struggle with this
我认为人们有时会在这方面感到困惑，
sometimes because what they'll say and
因为他们会反驳说：“
rebuttal to that is well I'm just so
我只是
busy Paul I'm so so busy I've got kids
太忙了。” 我真的很忙，我有孩子，还有
I've got you know mortgage to pay Etc I
房贷要还等等。我
have to say they are entirely right that
必须说，他们说得完全对，
we have a finite amount of time but in
我们的时间是有限的。但
that they're showing what they value
他们也从中展现了他们的价值观，他们珍视
kids and their life their ability to
孩子、珍视生活、珍视
live and eat that is a value that is a
生存和吃饭的能力，这才是
priority and this is also why I think
最重要的。这也是为什么我认为
our values should be viewed in
我们应该把价值观，
especially as it relates to like how we
特别是与我们如何
allocate our time as a as a list of
分配时间相关的价值观，看作是一份
priorities I this is most important then
优先级清单。比如，这件事最重要，然后是那件事，然后是那件事，然后是那件事，
this then this then this then this
然后是那件事。
because we can value 20 things it
因为我们可能重视20件事，但这
doesn't mean we're going to do them
并不意味着我们都会去做，
because we you know time is finite but
因为时间是有限的，但
values aren't necessarily they're
价值观却不一定是有限的。
they're not I completely agree it it it
我完全同意，这
should be a level of prioritization
应该是一种优先级排序，
right and we should own we should
我们应该
comfortably own what that is yes so if
坦然接受自己的价值观。所以，如果
it is time with your children then you
陪伴孩子的时间对你来说很重要，那么你就应该重视它，坚持
value that you know that's what you
你的
value stand by that because the more
价值观。因为
that you can stand by that and erect
你越能坚持它，并
boundaries around that the happier
围绕它设定界限，
you'll be the more fulfilled you'll be
你就会越快乐，越满足。
and you you can spot it in the language
可以从语言中看出端倪，
because if if I embodied what you just
因为如果我像你刚才
said when someone asks Steve why haven't
说的那样，当有人问史蒂夫为什么没
you gone to the gym my response would
去健身房时，我的回答会是“
be I had other
我有其他更
priorities it wouldn't be I can't right
重要的事”，而不是“我不能去”，
you know I couldn't or it wouldn't be
或者“我不能去”，也不会是
blame it wouldn't be excuses it would
责备或找借口，而是
literally be the the recognition that
真正地承认有
there was other priorities that won and
其他更重要的事优先，这没关系，这没关系，这没关系。
but it's so interesting so arranged
但这很有意思，包办
marriages people in arranged marriages
婚姻，包办婚姻中的人们
report high levels of satisfaction and
报告说满意度很高，而且
average and and and and even to to break
平均而言婚姻持续时间更长。甚至可以进一步分析，因为是由
the family making the decision right so
家庭做出决定，所以
the family is able to see things that
家庭能够看到
you may not be able to see so that's
你可能看不到的事情，这是其中
that's that's one big driver of it the
一个重要因素。
second driver of it is let's look at
第二个因素是，我们
traditional marriage now outside of a
现在来看看传统婚姻，而不是
ranged marriages right now and this is
包办婚姻。根据
Eli finle research 80% of current
伊莱·芬勒的研究，80%的现有
marriages are more dissatisfied than
婚姻比以往任何时候都更不满意，
they ever have been ever and 20% are
而20%的婚姻比以往任何时候都
more satisfied than they than they ever
更满意。
have been now now why is that it's
为什么会这样呢？原因就在于
because of what we were talking about
我们
previously and that is is that we now
之前讨论过的内容：我们现在
want so much more from our partner we we
对伴侣的期望值太高了。我们
want our partner to be our best friend
希望伴侣成为我们最好的朋友、
our lover our Co CEO our running buddy
爱人、共同CEO、跑步伙伴、
spiritual leader spiritual leader our
心理咨询师、精神导师，甚至是一起看
Netflix and chill buddy like we we want
Netflix放松的伙伴。我们
all of this now out of our partner and
现在想要伴侣做到这一切。
so what many people are recognizing is
很多人意识到，
they're waking up they're saying you
他们正在觉醒，他们说：“
know I can only get like 50% from from
我只能从
my partner of what I want or 60% and
伴侣那里得到我想要的50%或60%的东西。”因此，很多
many people are not satisfied as a
人并不满意。
result of that but the 20% are looking
但那20%的人正在审视
at their partner they're using all of
他们的伴侣，他们正在利用所有
these available tools we have we so much
可用的资源。我们掌握了大量
incredible data around how to have a
关于如何建立
successful relationship that if you are
成功关系的宝贵数据，如果你
putting in the work and your partner is
和你的伴侣都
putting in the work you can be more
付出努力，你们就能
satisfied than ever right and so that's
比以往任何时候都更加满意。这就是
the reason why a small percentage are
为什么一小部分人更满意的原因。这部分人
that group is more satisfied than the
比
average is because the average is not
平均水平更满意的部分原因是，平均水平的人并不满意。
satisfied so if you're in that that sort
如果你属于那
of 80% of unsatisfied people in their
80%的不满意人群，那么你就能获得满足感。 对于感情中不满足的人，
relationships is one solution to that to
一个解决办法是
encourage or facil itate your partner in
鼓励或帮助伴侣
meeting their needs in other places and
在其他地方满足他们的需求。
I say this because my partner lived in
我这么说是因为我的伴侣在
barley for two years and then I was
巴里住了两年，然后我
living here so there was this
搬到了这里，所以我们谈了
long-distance relationship where there
异地恋，
was we wouldn't see each other sometimes
有时长达
for 60 days for two months especially
60天甚至两个月都见不到面，尤其是在疫情
with the lockdowns and all that stuff it
封锁期间，简直太
was crazy and then we got to that point
疯狂了。后来
in our relationship where we realized
我们意识到，
that one of us has to move if this
如果这段感情要继续下去，我们其中一人必须搬家。
so does she move to to London from b or
所以，她要从巴里搬到伦敦，还是
do I move my life to Bary okay which is
我要搬到巴里？这真的
super difficult I was say pretty
很难。我当时想，好吧，好吧，好吧，
yeah yeah yeah I quit dragging down I
我不再拖延了，我
saw the podcast it's like my business is
看了播客，就像我的生意一样，
forget All for Love yeah but I I knew
忘了说“All for Love”吧。但是我知道
that I could never ask her to to move
我永远不能要求她搬
here I could never do that she had to
过来，我永远做不到，她必须
make that decision for herself because
自己做决定。因为
I've seen scenarios where there's
我见过很多这样的例子：
contempt when you move you you it's
当你搬家时，会产生怨恨、轻蔑等等，就
almost like you take on the
好像你承担了
responsibility of that person if you if
那个人的责任。如果
you tell them to come to your to your
你告诉他们…… 来到你那边，是啊，
first things I thought about
我首先想到的就是，
was I'm a bus person and if she doesn't
我是个事业型人士，如果她在
have a friendship group here a purpose
这里没有朋友圈，没有目标，没有
here work here then I'm going to be have
工作，那我就得
to be the source of all of those things
成为她这一切的来源，是的，
yes and that's terrifying yes and I tell
这很可怕。我告诉
you for the first part of our
你，在我们
relationship when she' moved here
关系的初期，她搬到这里的时候，
I felt like I did have to be those
我感觉我必须承担起这些
things once she' started her business
责任。后来她在
here and her with her business came a
这里创业，她的事业带来了
community and it came her own little
社群，带来了她自己的
tribe and her own sense of purpose and I
小圈子，也带来了她自己的目标感。
look over in the kitchen when I come
我下班回家，看到
back from work and she's on the laptop
她在厨房角落里对着笔记本电脑，
in the corner obsessed with her work and
全神贯注地工作，
I thought God yeah yeah yeah but that's
我心想，天哪，是啊，是啊，这就是
back in the day when you were talking
你之前说的
relationships oh oh yeah I mean that
恋爱关系第二阶段时的样子。哦，是啊，我的意思是，这就是
that's that's the reason why it's it's
为什么……这很
interesting why I mean to to to that
有意思。我想回答
original question of yours is that we
你最初的问题，是因为我们
now because we all have different goals
现在处于一种非常复杂的状态，因为我们都有不同的目标，
you know maybe in your relationship you
你知道，也许在…… 你们的关系，你
know it all it it it already sounds that
知道的，听起来
you and your girlfriend are interested
你和你的女朋友都
in self-actualization right you you want
对自我实现很感兴趣，对吧？你想
to flourish yeah you know of course you
蓬勃发展，当然你
want to flourish but some people may not
想蓬勃发展，但有些人可能并不
want to flourish if you go down maso's
渴望蓬勃发展。如果你仔细研究马索的
hierarchy of needs for some folks it's
需求层次理论，对一些人来说，
just about belonging or it could be just
归属感、
about self-esteem or it could be just
自尊或
the safety I just know I have someone
安全感才是最重要的。我知道有人
with me just the safety so we so we have
陪伴，这种安全感就是我们需要的。所以我们有
these different needs and I think that's
不同的需求。我认为，
why one of the most important things we
我们能为自己做的最重要的事情之一
can do for ourselves is to identify what
就是弄清楚
is it that we want out of this world and
我们想要什么，
then
然后
unapologetically go after it surround
毫不犹豫地去追求它。让
yourself with people who are going after
自己身边围绕着那些也在追求目标的人，无论是在
it romantically professionally socially
恋爱关系、事业还是社交方面。
you know find your tribe uh and that's
找到你的圈子，
where you'll thrive on that point as
你就能在那里蓬勃发展。
well you said about friends knowing you
你说过朋友比
when they tell you that this ain't the
你更了解你自己，也因此知道你应该追求什么。你觉得听朋友的话有多重要？ 他不是对的
one he ain't the guy oh man I had a
人，他不是那个人，哦，天哪，我
conversation recently with a friend who
最近和一个朋友（
I Shan name who you know we're all
我就不点名了）聊过，你知道，我们都
saying to this person listen this ain't
对这个人说：“听着，他不是对的
the guy and you can see this the Absolut
人。” 你也能看出这一点，
the point is absolutely not Landing you
重点是绝对不行。你肯定
must have seen this a million times all
见过无数次这种情况，总是这样，总是这样，总是这样。
the time all the time all the time if
如果
all of your friends are saying this
你所有的朋友都说“他
ain't the guy this ain't the
不是对的人，他不是对的
guy no matter what it will not work out
人”，那么无论如何，这段感情都不会成功，
100% of the times it it it it won't the
百分之百不会。
the the friend the I think there's
朋友说，我觉得
certain things that we did with this
我们通过这家婚介机构做的一些事情真的很有
were groundbreaking that was one if you
突破性。其中之一就是，如果你
can look at what your friends and family
看看你的朋友、家人
and all of the people who love you are
以及所有爱你的人都在
saying and they all say the same thing
说什么，他们都说同样的话，那就是
truth and how important is it to get
事实。在开始
your [__] together before you go into a
一段感情之前，把自己的事情处理好有多重要？
relationship I've always wondered this
我一直很想知道，你是先进入一段感情，然后
relationship and the situation fixes you
这段感情会治愈你，
or do you fix yourself then go into the
还是你先治愈自己再进入这段感情？
relationship you talk about this in the
你在《
book the idea that our satisfaction
想法》这本书里也谈到了这一点。 我们
levels in a relationship will vary based
在一段关系中的满意度会
on our satisfaction levels before the
根据恋爱前的满意度而变化。
relationship yes so this was one of the
是的，这可以说是
most enlightening I think pieces of what
最有启发性的观点之一。
we're not hearing what we hear in pop
我们经常在流行
culture all the time is if you have
文化中听到的是，拥有
shared values that's what makes the
共同的价值观才能缔造最
strongest marriage or that's what makes
牢固的婚姻或关系。
the strongest relationship some people
有些人甚至
say if you have great sex that's what
认为，性生活美满才能
makes the strongest relationship but
缔造最牢固的关系。但
actually what we found in the research
实际上，我们的研究发现，
here is if you walk into a relationship
如果你在进入一段关系之前就拥有
and you have a high level of
很高的满意度，那么你
highest level of satisfaction in the
在这段关系中就能获得最高的满意度。
relationship so the key is you want to
所以关键在于，你要
figure out how you could flourish you
找到让自己蓬勃发展的方法。卡罗尔·
know on your own on your own Carol riff
里夫（Carol Riff）
is one of the people who I don't think
是一位我认为
she gets enough attention out here in
在
the relationship science space or even
关系科学领域乃至整个
in the world right she's a brilliant
世界都未得到足够关注的人物。她是一位杰出的
researcher and in the 1980s she sat down
研究者，在20世纪80年代，她研究了所有关于
written about flourishing and then she
幸福感的理论家，
figures out the consensus what are all
总结了
of these great theorists saying about
这些伟大理论家关于
flourishing and well-being and she
幸福感和福祉的共识，并
created what's called The Six Dimensions
创建了所谓的“
of psychological well-being and I never
心理六维度”。 幸福感，我很少
hear anyone talk about this it's like
听到有人谈论它，但它却是
Concepts ever for us and what she's
我们生活中最重要的概念之一。她
outlined is that there's six areas we
概述了六个方面，
should be focused on if we want to
如果我们想在有伴侣
flourish with or without a partner one
或没有伴侣的情况下都能蓬勃发展，就应该关注这些方面。第一是
of them is personal development are you
个人发展：你是否走在
on the path to personal growth are you
个人成长的道路上？你是否在做
doing things to develop yourself right
正确的自我提升的事情？
number two do you have inspiration do
第二，你是否有灵感？
you have a goal that you are Marching
你是否有一个正在努力实现的
towards in life number three is autonomy
人生目标？第三是自主性：你是否感觉
feeling like you have control over your
自己能够掌控时间？
time next one number four is what's
第四是
called environmental mastery this is do
环境掌控：
you feel like the area that you're in
你是否感觉自己所处的环境——
physically the area that you're in the
你所在的地方，
city that you may live in the town that
你居住的城市或城镇——是否有
you may live in is it conducive to you
利于你
doing all the things that you want to do
做所有你想做的事情？
right in life next is having a strong
第三是
relationship with other people whether
与他人建立牢固的关系，无论是
it be romantically it could it could be
浪漫关系还是
platonically but do you feel like you
柏拉图式的关系，你是否感觉自己与他人
have connections do do you have friends
有联系？你是否拥有朋友？
right and last but not least is a
最后但同样重要的是，
concept that she calls self-acceptance
她称之为自我接纳的概念。
this is very important self-acceptance
自我接纳非常重要，它意味着
is knowing the demons that you have
了解你自身的缺点和不足。
inside and being okay with them it's
内心深处，坦然接受自己的缺点，就是
it's it's knowing and acknowledging that
明白并承认
you know I'm good but I do have some bad
自己有优点，也有缺点，
and I accept my bad if you are working
并且接受自己的缺点。如果你努力
towards all of those things all of those
做到这
six dimensions you will have the highest
六个方面，
level of well-being you'll reach
你就能达到最高的幸福感，实现
self-actualization and to your question
自我实现。至于你的问题，
doing with or without a partner and if
无论有没有伴侣，我们都应该这样做。如果
you could do it without a partner when
你在没有伴侣的情况下都能做到，那么当
you enter your partnership it will be
你进入伴侣关系时，你的关系会更加
that much stronger people that you've
牢固。你和那些
spoken to that are struggling in their
在感情中挣扎的人交谈过，
relationships do you think they have
你认为他们会认为
this opinion that the relationship is
感情关系能
going to fix their problems yes yeah I I
解决他们的问题吗？是的，我
I think we walk into relationships and
认为我们进入一段感情关系时，
we think it's the end we think that's
会觉得一切都结束了，以为万事大吉了。但事实并非如此，这只是
work begins and we have to change this
工作的开始。我们必须改变这种想法。
and a lot of this has to do with and you
很多时候，这都与……有关。你
know and I put some of the blame on me
知道，我承认自己也有责任。
you know I think some of this is
我认为部分原因在于
television you know some of this is is
电视，
is is the you know a lot of people call
很多人称之为
relationships uh
感情关系的“迪士尼化”。
we misunderstand and misinterpret our
我们常常误解和曲解自己
role in
在
relationships how I I fundamentally
恋爱关系中的角色。我
believe that the number one reason for
坚信，分手的首要原因
breakups is not we we hear reports all
并非我们自己。我们总是听到各种说法，比如
the time that it's Finance it's
经济问题、出轨等等，都不是。真正的原因是
things you know what it is it's we pick
我们
bad Partners we select the wrong
选错了
Partners or we don't make the selection
伴侣，或者根本没有做出选择。
at all many of us and unfortunately I
不幸的是，
see this a I see this a lot with
我经常看到这种情况，尤其是在
heterosexual women is they allow
异性恋女性身上。她们任由别人
themselves to be selected opposed to
选择，而不是自己
making the choice themselves so so the
做出选择。所以，首先，
first part is is are we choosing the
我们是否在选择最适合自己的伴侣？这是第一点。
then once we have chosen the partner
其次，一旦我们选择了伴侣，
then are we working together to help our
我们是否在共同努力，帮助
partner unveil their best self you know
对方展现最好的自己？你知道
the Michelangelo effect and Eli finle
米开朗基罗效应吗？埃利·芬勒（Eli Finle）
writes about this where you know
对此有所论述。
Michelangelo would never look at a stone
米开朗基罗不会看着一块石头
and say I'm going to carve this
说：“我要雕刻这座
beautiful statue instead he'd look at
美丽的雕像”，而是会看着
the stone and say I'm going to unveil
石头说：“我要揭开
this beautiful piece of art this
这件美丽的艺术品，这座蕴藏
beautiful statue that's in the stone
在石头里的美丽雕像。”
that's how we should look at our partner
我们也应该这样看待我们的伴侣。 我们每个人内心
is that we all have this beautiful
都有一座美丽的
statue within us and when you find the
雕像，当你找到
strongest partner that allows you to see
最强大的伴侣，你就能看到这一点。
that you know I know you've had Dr W
我知道你之前
Dinger on Phenom like he says it in in
在Phenom节目里听过W·丁格博士的演讲，就像他在
his research you live longer you're
研究中提到的那样，你会活得更久、更
happier you make more money you know you
快乐、赚得更多，你会
get all of the benefits When you choose
获得所有这些好处。
a strong partner but if you choose a
但如果你选择了一个
weak partner not only do you not live as
软弱的伴侣，你不仅会活得更
long not only are you not as happy not
短，不仅不会更快乐，不仅会更
only are you more unhealthy but but you
不健康，而且你
can literally suffer not just emotional
还会遭受真正的痛苦，不仅仅是情感
and psychological distress there is a
和心理上的折磨。世界各地的
rise of domestic violence that is
家庭暴力事件都在增加，
around the world so you could literally
所以你真的会因为
suffer death death by choosing the wrong
选择错误的
partner and so it goes to show how
伴侣而丧命。这足以说明这个
important the decision is this this is
决定有多么重要，
this is a life or death decision I want
这是一个生死攸关的决定。我想深入探讨
to go into all of those things you said
你刚才提到的所有
about selecting selecting poorly and the
关于选择错误伴侣以及
decision that comes with Psychopaths and
与精神病患者、
narcissists and all that stuff um you
自恋者等等相关的生死抉择。你
know what's interesting is when you say
知道吗，有趣的是，当你告诉我一切都
to me that the work starts at the
始于
relationship there's part of me that
关系时，我的一部分想法是：
oh do you know what I mean because in
你知道吗？ 我的意思是，在
the movies I was thinking of all these
电影里，我想到了
movies I'd seen in New York where
我在纽约看过的所有那些电影，剧情总是反转，
there's a Twist there's a turn and then
然后是
there's a happily ever after and the
幸福美满的结局，
movie ends and and you think when the
电影就结束了。你会觉得，在
we've watched for 10 20 30 years you
我们看过10年、20年、30年的所有这些电影里，当电影结束时，一切就结束了，
think that is the end you think they
你会觉得他们从此过上了
live happily ever after I watched the
幸福的生活。我见证了
turmoil I watched the battle and then
动荡，见证了争斗，然后
they live happily ever after if that
他们从此过上了幸福的生活。如果这部
movie was to be extended any movie we've
电影要延长，任何我们
seen romantic movie what you'd then see
看过的爱情电影，你看到的都会是
is another 30 years of like [__] but
另外30年的狗血剧情，但
we don't see that so I was just thinking
我们并没有看到。所以我就在想，
like where did we get this idea from
我们从哪里得到了“找到另一半就万事大吉”这种想法？是的，这种想法正在
that the work stops when we find the
酝酿。
so it's coming from a couple places one
它来自几个方面：首先，
is that's where it did stop at one point
在某个阶段，一切确实就此停止。
you think about the pragmatic stage the
想想务实阶段，想想
Romantic stage that was all you needed
浪漫阶段，那时
you just needed the partner it didn't
你只需要一个伴侣，其他都不
matter you didn't have to do any work
重要，你不需要
with the partner so so we we have gotten
和伴侣一起努力。所以我们就有了
this honestly as a as a society but also
这种想法。 说实话，这不仅关乎社会，也关乎
it's what pop culture it's what media
流行文化、媒体以及它们给
it's it's it's what it feeds us but I
我们灌输的东西。但我
would say
认为，
don't look at it as hard distasteful
不要把它看作是艰苦乏味的
work yeah instead here's a better way
工作。相反，这里有一个更好的方法，
let's reframe it reframe the negative
让我们重新定义它，重新定义负面的东西。对吧？
right is this podcast right
这个播客很棒！
Incredible One skill you're probably
你可能会学到一项很棒的技能，其中
one of which I'm sure is your active
一项我确信是你的积极
listening is off the charts now compared
倾听能力。
to what it maybe was day one now if you
与第一天相比，你的积极倾听能力肯定突飞猛进。如果你
thought active listening I'm going to
认为积极倾听——我将
learn active listening during this
在这个播客中学习积极倾听——会很
grueling I don't think so I think that
辛苦吗？我不这么认为。我认为
you probably saw that as a great life
你可能把它看作是一项很棒的生活
skill I can come in here I'm going to
技能。我来到这里，
not only meet all I'm going to do all
不仅会遇到所有人，会做所有这些
this incredible things but I'm also
很棒的事情，还会
going to develop skills and these skills
培养技能，这些技能可以
are transferable to everything I do
应用到我做的每一件事中。这就是
that's how we should look at our
我们应该看待我们之间的
relationship look at it that way you are
关系的方式。你会学到很多可以应用到
are transferable across your life and as
你生活中的技能，随着
you develop those skills the whole Tide
你不断提高这些技能，整个“潮水
Rises you're going to uh develop new
上涨”计划也会随之改变。 培养新
skills and and and better Master new
技能，更好地掌握新
skills and then apply those to your
技能，然后将它们应用到你的
business apply those to to your platonic
事业中，应用到你的柏拉图式
relationship so it it's it's it's a
关系中，这是一件
wonderful thing
很棒的事情。
and when you are in a secure
当你处于一段稳定的
relationship it's boring as
关系中时，它简直无聊透顶，非常
hell it's boring which is why you know
无聊。这就是为什么……我
uh not to get myself into trouble but
不想惹麻烦，但是
you know when you're watching television
你知道，当你看电视，
and you're watching these shows around
看那些关于
Rel relationships uh actually I I'll
人际关系的节目时……实际上，
give an examp I will give an example um
我举个例子，
when I got here to the UK uh I started
我刚到英国的时候，参加了一个
on a on a show called slubs go dating
叫《Slubs Go Dating》的节目，
and then I very quickly went to a show
然后很快我又参加了一个
called Married at First Sight UK and
叫《Married at First Sight UK》的节目。
when I was on Married at First Site UK
我在《Married at First Sight UK》的
my first series it was a full docu
第一季是一个完整的纪录片
series and we matched couples and it was
系列，我们为情侣们配对，但它很
boring you know why it was boring
无聊。你知道为什么无聊吗？
because they all loved each other they
因为他们都彼此相爱，都很
all really liked each other and out of
喜欢对方。在
that group of four couples three of them
那四对情侣中，有三对
are together today wow right but you ask
现在还在一起，哇，对吧？但是你问
anyone in the UK did you see that series
任何一个英国人，你有没有看过这个系列，
they'll say no we didn't see that
他们会说没有，我们没看过。 一开始很
because it's boring and then you change
无聊，然后你改变
things and you get couples who can still
一下，你会发现有些情侣虽然还能继续
work but there's tension right for a
交往，但因为
variety of reasons there's tension and
各种各样的原因，彼此之间会有矛盾。
then it gets exciting and so one thing
然后，事情就变得刺激起来。所以
that I always say is great love looks
我常说，美好的爱情看起来很
boring boring but it feels great you
无聊，但感觉很棒。你
know good love it it feels it it good
知道，美好的爱情，感觉很棒。
love looks boring but it feels great
爱情看起来很无聊，但感觉很棒。
men men are struggling it seems I think
男人们似乎正在经历困境。我觉得，
you know the more and more I talk on
你知道，我在
this show about dating apps and what
这个节目里谈论约会软件以及在如今这个比以往任何时候都更加数字化的
it's like to be a man in this dating
约会环境下做男人是什么感觉，
conversation always emerges in the in
总会在
the in the com sort of like the comment
评论
sections and stuff about men's struggles
区之类的地方出现关于男性困境的讨论。
here because you know these dating apps
因为你知道，这些约会软件
they seem to
似乎并
be not welld designed for the like
没有为那
bottom 50% of men what is what what are
50%的男性设计得那么好。你
your thoughts on this yeah I'm I'm I'm
对此有什么看法？是的，我同意你的看法。
with you you know what I like about the
你知道，我喜欢
conversation today is we're finally
今天的讨论的一点是，我们终于
acknowled it's it's it's okay to
承认了，
acknowledge that you know men are
承认这一点是可以的。你知道，男性正在
getting crapped on you know I I feel
遭受不公平的待遇。你知道，我觉得就在
like just a year ago if you said that oh
一年前，如果你 有人说，哦
no what are you talking about you know
不，你在说什么？你知道
we're still in the patriarchy you can't
我们仍然生活在父权制社会里，你不能……不，
no men are struggling High suicide rates
男人们正在苦苦挣扎。高自杀率、
highest levels of loneliness highest
极高的孤独感、最严重的
issues around mental health men are
心理健康问题，男人们正在
struggling and the fact that we can just
苦苦挣扎。而我们现在可以
ex talk about that and all acknowledge
谈论这些，并且都承认，
okay let's figure out how to deal with
好吧，让我们想想办法解决这个问题，这
this is a good place to begin right but
是一个很好的开始，对吧？但是，但是，
but but now we now we have to begin you
但是，现在我们必须开始……你
know it begins with the awareness and
知道，这始于意识的觉醒和
talking about it it extends into
讨论，它延伸到为
creating safe spaces for men to be able
男性创造安全的空间，让他们能够
to talk I love that what you see now is
畅所欲言。我很高兴看到现在
you see these podcast
出现了这些播客
communities um creating these spaces
社区，它们创造了这样的空间，让
where men feel like they can be
男性感到自己被
acknowledged and seen and that allows
认可和被看见，这使得他们能够
for there to be connection with other
与其他经历
men going through those same challenges
同样挑战的男性建立联系，从而
which creates camaraderie and helps you
建立友谊，并帮助他们
to uh to to break out of that loneliness
摆脱孤独。所以，
so so so we're we're we're on the path
我们走在正确的道路上，
uh but we have to acknowledge some of
但是我们必须承认
those larger trends that we see I know
我们看到的一些更大的趋势。我知道
Richard Reeves uh talks about this quite
理查德·里夫斯在他的《
a bit phenomenal book of boys and men
男孩与男人》一书中对此进行了很多探讨，
where you can see uh just the levels of
你可以看到
unemployment the lower levels of
失业率有多高。 男性教育程度较低，
the high levels of uh of drug usage the
吸毒率较高，
high levels of what uh Richard Reeves
理查德·里夫斯
calls sedation essentially is uh drug
所说的“镇静剂”（本质上是指吸毒和
usage uh pornography watching where uh
观看色情片）使用率也较高，
you have a large number of men just
很多男性只是为了缓解
sedating themselves out of pain right
痛苦和孤独而用这些方式麻痹自己。
out of loneliness and so I I think we're
所以我认为我们现在是着手解决
in a great place to begin working on the
这个
problem but it's a hell of a problem in
问题的绝佳时机，但这确实是个棘手的问题。在
your book on uh page 72 it says that in
你的书中第72页，你提到在
the Tinder research you found that one
Tinder的研究中，你发现
of the main reasons men aren't in
男性不谈恋爱的主要原因之一
relationships is because of rejection
是害怕被拒绝，
yes fear of rejection yes number one and
没错，就是害怕被拒绝，是第一大原因。
and many people would laugh at that they
很多人可能会对此嗤之以鼻，他们会说：“
would laugh at that stat what men walk
男人
to me all the time so how is it that men
经常跟我说，为什么男人
are fearful of rejection but the fact of
会害怕被拒绝呢？”但事实是，
the matter is that the majority of men
大多数男性
report the number one reason why they
表示，
believe they can't find a significant
他们找不到
other is the fear of being rejected
另一半的首要原因是害怕被拒绝。
think about that and that's not just in
想想看，这不仅仅指现实生活中，也包括
person that's online feeling as if you
网络世界。他们感觉自己好像会被拒绝。
reject me and to me that speaks to
被拒绝对我来说，这关乎
self-esteem to me that speaks to
自尊，关乎
self-love to me that speaks to selfworth
自爱，关乎自我价值。
and so therefore we have to really
因此，我们必须认真
evaluate the the the why the the why why
评估背后的原因，为什么会这样？
is that you know but I think this is
但我认为这一点非常
such an important point and this is why
重要，这就是为什么
we have to look back let's look at
我们必须回顾
history why is it the case that the
历史。为什么
Calvin Klein model or why is it the case
卡尔文·克莱恩的模式如此盛行？为什么社会
that the higher status person gets more
地位更高的人会获得更多
interaction if you think back to
互动？想想看，
pragmatic right if you were a
如果你是一个
woman what did you need to
女人，你需要什么才能
survive uh I needed a mate that would
生存？我需要一个能
protect me exactly now the protection
保护我的伴侣。保护主要有两种
would come in one of two things and I
方式。我这么
say that because at some point I'm going
说是因为，在某个时候，我可能会
to be eight and a half months pregnant
怀孕八个半月，那时
and I I ain't going to be able to hunt
我无法狩猎、
no you know or forage or I don't know
采集，或者做其他事情。
exactly and so so you need to have the
所以，你需要
protection and the protection came in in
保护。保护有两种
one of two ways one physicality right
方式：一是身体素质，比如
soone just strong and fight but the
强壮和战斗力；
other was high social status resources
二是高社会地位带来的资源，这些资源会
bring resources and therefore you know
带来更多资源。因此，你知道，
you'd have the protection because of
你会拥有…… 正是因为
that so how long did that
这种保护，这种保护持续了多久？是的，几乎贯穿了整个
of human history so we have through
人类历史。通过
Evolution this has been indoctrinated
进化，这种观念已经根深蒂固地融入了
into our into our system and what is
我们的系统。但
rarely talked about is so you know there
很少有人谈及的是，
were millions of men throughout history
历史上有数百万男性
who were not the Calvin Klein not the
并非卡尔文·克莱恩，身材
biggest didn't have the social status so
矮小，社会地位低下。那么，
what happened to them in history do you
他们在历史上遭遇了什么？你
know what happened to them most of them
知道他们中的大多数人遭遇了什么吗？
they were the ones sent to
他们中的大多数人被送上了
war these were the men fighting for
战场。这些男人为
whatever country the the these were the
不同的国家而战。
men when you when you watch Napoleon and
当你观看拿破仑的传记片，
you see oh my God the Battle of waterl
看到沃特尔战役时，
you had tens of thousands of people
成千上万的人
who's dying it's those men it's not the
死去，而死的正是这些人。不是那些
high stat status men it's not it's not
社会地位显赫的人，不是那些光鲜亮丽的
the Calvin kin looking right it's those
卡尔文·克莱恩，而是这些
men were dying and we've reached a point
普通人。如今，我们社会发展到了一个阶段，
in society where we're no longer
我们不再进行那样的
fighting Wars like that we're fighting
战争，而是使用
with drones and missiles you have
无人机和导弹作战。
millions upon Millions upon millions of
数以百万计的
men sitting there saying okay now what
男人坐在那里，茫然地问自己：那我呢？那
about me what about me and this is the
我呢？这就是
problem this is where we are what about
问题所在，这就是我们现在的处境。
men what were they selecting
男人呢？ 他们是不是在
for they were selecting for youth
挑选年轻、
fertility fertility yeah they they
生育能力强的男性？是的，他们
wanted youth which which spoke to
想要年轻，这体现了
fertility uh and that ran through time
生育能力，而且这种观念一直延续至今。这就是
and that's the reason why you see a
为什么你会看到一些
woman who you know I talk about this in
女性……你知道，我在
the book there's this golden mean golden
书中也提到过，有一个黄金分割的
mean I read this and it was the first
概念。我读过这本书，那是
time I'd ever heard of this idea of the
我第一次听说
golden mean but it was super interesting
黄金分割这个概念，但它非常有趣。
the golden mean explained why my
黄金分割解释了为什么我的
girlfriend seems to like my shoulders
女朋友似乎喜欢我的肩膀，
she doesn't care if I get fat I swear to
她不在乎我变胖。我发誓，有
you I asked her one day I was like what
一天我问她，
do you prefer cuz she asked me she said
你喜欢我什么，因为她问我，她说
what features do you prefer on me and
你喜欢我身上的哪些特征。
obviously I knew that was a trap so I
显然我知道这是个陷阱，所以我
said
说了
everything I'm not stupid but then when
所有，我又不傻。但当
she asked the question she I asked her
她再次问我这个问题时，我也反问了她，我说
features do you prefer on me she was
你喜欢我身上的哪些特征？她说，
like your shoulders yeah and I was like
你的肩膀。我说，
really I was like I thought they said
真的吗？我以为她们说的是，我
you wanted like I thought women wanted a
以为女人想要的是
six-pack she was like she was holding my
六块腹肌。她一边说着，一边扶着我的
shoulders she was like your shoulders
肩膀，说，你的肩膀。
yes and then I read this golden mean
然后我
thing in your book and I was like ah
在你的书中读到了关于黄金分割的内容，我…… 啊，对对，就是这样，
yeah yeah that's that's how I I I could
我……
you know what's interesting I spot
你知道吗，有趣的是，我注意到
everyone and I almost am calculating
每个人，我几乎都在计算
golden mean because I'm always thinking
黄金分割，因为我总是像个
as a Matchmaker like I can match that so
媒人一样思考，觉得我可以把他们配对。
the the golden mean has stood throughout
黄金分割在历史上一直存在，
calculation for for men and women for
男女的计算方法不同。
women the calculation is the difference
女性的计算方法是
between waste and hips right so it's the
腰围和臀围之差，也就是腰围
percentage of your waist to your hips so
占臀围的百分比。
if on average your waist is 70% of what
如果平均而言，你的腰围是臀围的70%，那就被
your hips are that is considered to be
认为是
fertile right you're considered to be at
生育力旺盛的，对吧？你被认为处于
optimal you know you're optimal for
最佳状态，你知道，
fertilization in in essence and you
本质上来说，你处于受孕的最佳状态。你
could see that ratio tested throughout
可以看到这个比例在历史上和不同文化中都得到
time and you could see that ratio tested
验证，这在
to an Eastern collectivist society and
东方集体主义社会中很少见，因为在西方
individualistic society and so the
个人主义社会中，这种情况很罕见。所以
golden mean stands through time and the
黄金分割经受住了时间的考验。
reason why it's so interesting is
它之所以如此有趣，是
because you look at like Twiggy in the
因为你看看像Twiggy这样的女性，
1970s I think uh in the UK and you say
我想，她在20世纪70年代的英国，你会说，
gosh Twiggy so thin but she still had a
天哪，Twiggy那么瘦，但她仍然……
70% golden mean you you look at the you
70%是黄金分割率，你看，
know people talk about the the Kim
人们都在谈论金·卡
Kardashians of the world she has less
戴珊，她的身材比例不到
than 70% she's probably like 50% right
70%，可能只有50%左右。
golden mean and so the golden mean is
黄金分割率是衡量
the optimal measure of what we just
我们认为的性感和生育能力的最佳标准，
average and so that hasn't been
平均而言，它不受
influenced by you know magazines and
杂志、媒体之类的影响。
with scientists think that's an eight
科学家们认为黄金分割率是8，
hum yes they think that that's an eight
没错，他们认为是8，
but it is it is impacted by culture so
但它确实会受到文化的影响。
you go into different subcultures and
不同的亚文化群体对
of the golden mean right so maybe it's
黄金分割率的理解可能有所不同，所以也许
more than 70% or should I say less than
超过70%或者应该说低于
70% could be what's considered more
70%的身材比例会被认为更有
attractive so it is influenced but on
吸引力。所以它会受到文化的影响，但
average that is it and the reason why I
平均而言就是这样。我这么
say that is it is because uh many men
说的原因是，很多男人
would argue oh no you'll say what what
会反驳说，什么？什么？你是
are you are you you're you're a breast
胸控？
man you're a leg man like what what what
腿控？这就像
is it like it's a Thanksgiving dinner
感恩节大餐一样，
you know what I mean and uh those could
你懂我的意思吧？ 嗯，这些
be characteristics and features that you
特征可能让你
find sexy and attractive but on average
觉得性感迷人，但平均而言，
this is what will um what will light up
这才是最能打动
most most men and then for me for for
大多数男人的。对我来说，对于
women when they're looking at a a man
女性来说，当她们审视一个男人时，
the golden mean is the difference
黄金分割指的是
between shoulders and waist and so if
肩宽和腰围之间的比例。如果
you have if your waist is 70% or less
你的腰围是肩宽的70%或更少，
than your shoulders then that is
那么这被
considered to be what someone who could
认为代表着一个能够保护你的人。这就是黄金分割的由来。
you know and therefore throughout
因此，在
hundreds of thousands of years of of of
数十万年的
of of History we get to the point where
历史长河中，我们逐渐形成了一种观念：
okay it's sexy why is it sexy I don't
好吧，他很性感。为什么性感？我不
know he just look sexy no the reason why
知道，他只是看起来很性感。不，他
I look sexy is because ultimately back
看起来很性感的原因是，归根结底，在过去，
in the day he could have been a
他可能是一个
protector so that's where that comes
保护者。这就是黄金分割的由来。
from and in the matchmaking Community
在婚介行业，
what I used to do all the time is if I
我以前经常这样做：如果我的
had a client who was you know say a male
客户是男性，
client and he didn't really represent
他的身材并不符合
the the golden mean I'd say put on this
黄金分割，我会建议他穿上这件……这件……这件……这件……这件……
this this uh this this Blazer here you
你
know wide shoulder pad Blazer go out
知道的，宽肩垫西装外套，然后去
there on that date um you know so the
约会。所以，
golden mean is something that has stood
黄金分割是一种…… 经受住了
the test of time so many people are
时间的考验，所以今晚很多人都会
going to be doing like shoulder
做肩上
pressing tonight that's crazy that's all
推举，这太疯狂了，
you need to do yeah a little bit of
你只需要做一点
shoulder press that's it that's so crazy
肩上推举就够了，这太疯狂了，
um but it but it makes evolutionary
嗯，但这在进化论上是
sense that there
有道理的，对吧？
is is it proportions the right word that
比例，这个词
we would associate with fertility or you
我们通常会联想到生育能力或者
protection what's this concept in
保护。
chapter 4 you talk about the concept of
第四章里你提到的“
mate value uh yeah this is this is I
伴侣价值”是什么概念？嗯，是的，我
feel like the whole book now is
觉得整本书都在
controvers
讨论这个概念。先
disclaim this is a another topic that a
声明一下，这是另一个
lot of people want to push back on right
很多人都想反驳的话题。
mate value is a
伴侣价值是一个
evolutionary
进化
psychology term that is around
心理学术语，它指的是
technically what value do we bring to
我们在择偶市场中能带来什么价值。
the mating Marketplace because when you
因为
think about uh you know our evolution is
想想我们的进化，
that we go on one or two paths in mating
我们在择偶方面会走一条或两条路，
we call it dating evolutionary they're
我们称之为约会，进化论称之为
calling it mating long-term mating or
长期择偶或
short-term mating right now short-term
短期择偶。短期择偶
mating is a separate Beast short-term
是另一回事，短期择偶
mating is literally I want to have sex
就是“我今晚想做爱”，
tonight therefore you're going to look
所以你会关注对方的
at different characteristics you're not
各种特征，你不会在意
going to care if you can trust the
是否信任
person you're not going to care like
对方，你不会在意对方的外表，
like and that really might not mean
而这些对
anything to you that's short-term ating
你来说可能根本无关紧要。这就是短期约会，
long-term mating is much different
长期择偶则截然不同。
long-term mating is just okay I'm
长期伴侣关系固然不错，但我
looking for a partner for life and part
想要的是终身伴侣。
of the calculation that we're doing
我们内心
innately the calculation that we're
深处会进行一番权衡，那就是
doing is what do we value the person
我们如何看待这个人。这和
it's no different than someone saying oh
别人评价一个人没什么区别，比如“
yeah he's a he's a nine or or or she
他9分”、“
she's a 10 you know 10 out of 10 she's a
她10分”，或者“
10 in essence that's what mate value is
10分满分”。本质上，这就是伴侣价值。
but I look at mate value as all of the
但我认为伴侣价值是
ingredients that we bring to the table
我们自身所有特质的总和。
look it is about status in our job yeah
没错，外表很重要，工作地位也很
that's important but it's also about how
重要，但善良、举止、自信等等也同样重要。
when when we walk into a room all of
所有
these pieces add up to mate value but
这些因素共同构成了伴侣价值。
the reason why I say it's it's so
之所以说
important to know is because mate value
了解伴侣价值如此重要，是因为它会
will also change based on the
根据不同的情境而变化。
context for example if I take so I keep
例如，如果
if if I take you Stephen and I bring you
我带你去弗吉尼亚州的里士满，而你就是斯蒂芬，那么你的伴侣价值就会有所不同。
to Richmond Virginia where my wife is
妻子
from and we go to a restaurant you walk
来自里士满，我们去一家餐厅，你一走进去，
in everyone is mesmerized by you the
所有人都被你迷住了。
moment you open your mouth yeah amazing
你一开口，哇，太棒了！
everyone is where is it
大家都在问：“你来自哪里？”（
[Laughter]
笑声）里士满，
postcode
邮编是……（
Richmond a note
注：
here everyone is the moment the moment
此处为Richmond的邮政编码）大家一听到
that you speak wow I've never heard an
你说话，就惊叹道：“哇，我从没听过这样的
accent like that tell me more about you
口音！跟我说说你吧！”
right they're intrigued it's what I call
他们很感兴趣。这就是我所说的“
the premium effect that lands on top of
溢价效应”，它叠加在
the mate value right but we have to
伴侣价值之上。但我们必须
understand that there is a value that we
明白，我们在
assign people when we are mating or
择偶或约会时会给对方赋予一个价值。你
dating you conveniently skipped over the
巧妙地略过了
one about having kids oh yeah yeah yeah
关于生孩子的那一点。哦，是啊是啊，
no no but so having kids it goes up or
没错。所以，生孩子会
it it brings your value up or it brings
提升你的价值，或者
your value down now it depends on what
降低你的价值。这取决于
your partner is seeking so if you if if
你的伴侣想要什么。所以，
you if CH so chances are let's say that
假设
you are a woman uh you have children and
你是一位女性，你有孩子，而
you are uh you're you're dating a a man
你正在和一个
who does not yet have children and wants
还没有孩子但想要
to have children chances are that is
孩子的男人约会，那么在
going to lower in his eyes on average
他眼里，你的价值很可能会降低。平均而言，
that's going to lower the that's going
这会降低你的价值。
to lower your perceived mate value
降低你对他的择偶价值认知。但是，
however however if he has children or
如果他有孩子，或者年纪稍大一些，
maybe he's a little bit older or what
或者出于其他任何
for for whatever the reason he could
原因，你都可以把这看作是一个优势。关键在于，真正
context that changes your mate value and
改变你择偶价值的是环境，这一点
that's very important the context is
非常重要。环境决定一切。
what changes it so this premium effect
所以，
you talked about then when you're
你刚才提到的“溢价效应”，当你
talking about um Richmond Virginia how
谈到弗吉尼亚州里士满时，
can one use that to increase my chance
如何利用这一点来增加
of finding someone to fall in love with
找到真爱的机会呢？请你详细解释一下“
what you mean by the premium effect is
溢价效应”的含义，是指
it being a scarce commodity in a certain
在特定环境下的稀缺性吗？是的，正是如此。
environment yeah that's exactly or a
或者说，
desirable commodity in a certain
在特定环境下的可贵性，就是
environment it it's being scarce scarce
稀缺性。
okay yeah so when we started the
好的，我们创办
matchmaking agency it was focused
婚介机构时，
exclusively for black women and the
只专注于服务黑人女性。
reason why is because I felt as if black
原因是我觉得黑人
women were being highly discriminated
女性
against in the matchmaking
在婚介
space and so I was trying everything and
领域受到了严重的歧视。所以我尝试了各种方法，然后
so I thought you know what I'm going to
我想，不如让
do I'm going to start putting my clients
我的客户注册
on dating apps and I will act as them
约会软件，由我来扮演她们的角色。
and I saw that they were not getting
但我发现这种方法并没有
traction is that statistically
奏效，这是有统计数据的吗？ 事实
proven I'd love to know yeah you know I
证明，我很想知道。是的，
will say from all of my experience in
根据我多年的
matchmaking it was that black women got
婚介经验，黑人女性
less matches on dating apps less swipes
在约会软件上的匹配率更低，滑动次数也更少。
it it in in my time when I was running
在我经营
that dating agency absolutely absolutely
那家约会机构的时候，这一点毋庸置疑，毫无疑问。
there's lots of reasons one reason is
原因有很多，其中一个原因是，除了
that when it comes to outside of gen Z
Z世代之外，其他世代，比如
so if you look at Millennials you look
千禧一代、
at Gen X you look at baby boomers and at
X世代、婴儿潮一代，在Z世代
that time gen Z wasn't yet on dating
还没开始使用约会
apps we're talking about Millennials and
软件的时候，我们说的是千禧一代及
higher we typically choose ethnicity
以后的世代，他们通常会优先考虑种族，而不是其他任何因素。
over every other category so ethnicity
所以种族
ended up being one of the first
成了择偶的首要
selections of a partner and we would
考虑因素之一，我们会
either include you or exclude you based
根据
on ethnicity jenz has changed this and
种族来决定是否推荐你。Z世代改变了这一切，
I'm and I'm so happy to see this genz is
我很高兴看到这一点。Z世代是
the first generation to at majority have
第一代对
interest in everyone so on Tinder for
所有人都感兴趣的人。例如，在Tinder上，
example we see that 80% of our gen Z
我们看到80%的Z世代用户
they are not just open but they have
不仅持开放态度，而且还和不同
dated someone outside of their ethnicity
种族的人约会过。
and I believe that we're entering this
我相信…… 进入
new phase of what I call we are we are
我称之为“我们是跨界的”这个新阶段，
inter everything we are inter ethnic
我们是跨种族、
International
国际化、
interreligious that to me is is is is
跨宗教的，这对我来说很
beautiful but that didn't happen for
美好，但千禧一代没有经历这一切，
for Gen X and definitely not for baby
X世代也没有，婴儿
boomer so ethnicity was number one so
潮一代更没有。种族是首要因素，正
because of that and because of the pools
因为如此，也因为
of uh black men on dating apps of that
约会软件上那个
age range were so much smaller that you
年龄段的黑人男性数量少得可怜，所以
black women so that's what was driving
黑人女性的选择率非常低。这就是导致人们对黑人女性
the low low low perceived interest but
兴趣度极低的原因。但
what I didn't like what was happening is
我不喜欢的是，
you would see this data come out uh you
你会看到这样的数据：
know black women are not selected or not
黑人女性没有被选中，没有被
swiped on or whatever it may be and it
滑动等等，然后就被
would be projected as black women are
解读为黑人女性
not desirable which is app like the most
不受欢迎。这简直是
ridiculous thing in the world I was like
世界上最荒谬的事情，我当时就想：
what are you talking about but the
你们在说什么？但
reason why is because they were taking
原因在于，他们只是利用这些
these small data sets and essentially
小样本数据，就
claiming this larger narrative based on
基于这些小样本数据得出了一个更大的结论。
this small data set and so when I was
所以，当我
experimenting with those uh W with with
用
my clients I then said okay what would
我的客户做实验时，我想，
happen if I put my black female clients
如果我让我的黑人女性客户
onto J date right Jewish date you know
使用Jdate，会发生什么呢？ 你知道，我当时在犹太约会网站上认识他们，
and they were not Jewish like they were
但他们其实不是犹太人，他们是
Ultra Christian right what would happen
极端基督徒，对吧？结果会怎么样呢？
so I started putting them on J date
所以我开始把他们放到JDate上，结果
phenomenal success
非常成功，真的非常成功，非常
success there was a percentage of people
成功！一部分人的
who responded who were crude why are you
回复很粗鲁，比如“你来
here there was a percentage of people
这里干嘛？”；一部分人的回复
who responded who were obviously
明显带有性幻想，比如“
fetishizing oh I want to do this to you
哦，我想对你做这个”，对
right but then there was a percentage of
吧？但也有一部分
people who were just curious let's see
人只是好奇，比如“我们来看看
why did you that's interesting I you're
你为什么来这里？真有意思，
why are you here like let's let's have
你为什么在这里？”；“我们来
this conversation and the
聊聊吧。”互动非常
plentiful and what I realized there is
多。我意识到，
assigned there was a extra value that
这里存在一种溢价效应，在这个领域，
they got by being the scarce commodity
他们因为稀缺而获得了额外的价值。
in in this space and so my objective
所以我的目标就是把我
with a lot of my clients was to take
的客户
them and put them in places where they
放到稀缺的环境中，这
are few that's so interesting and and we
很有意思。我们
scarce in real life is it going to like
在现实生活中也可以这样做，我们可以把自己置于稀缺的环境中，比如加入
a different type of sports club or you
某种类型的体育俱乐部，或者你
know what what what is that yeah so I um
知道的，那是什么？嗯，
I I try this out here I have a friend
我在这里试了一下，我有个朋友
who lives in hartfordshire she is a
住在…… 她住在哈特福德郡，是个
white woman friend 30
30多岁的白人女性朋友，
mid-30s uh completely open to meeting
非常乐于结识
everyone right she's like Paul I'm
所有人。她跟我说：“保罗，我是
single I don't know what to do I said
单身，不知道该怎么办。”我说：“好吧，那就这样吧。
all right here here's what you do come
来
on down to South London I want you to go
南伦敦吧，我想让你去
Brixton and I want you to go down there
布里克斯顿的黑人文化档案馆看个展览，
and you just tell me what happened she
你去之后告诉我发生了什么。”她
went down she was like oh my God it was
去了之后说：“我的天哪，太
crazy I met blah blah blah blah blah and
疯狂了！我遇到了……等等等等。”
and and and the point was that she put
重点是，她把
herself in a place where she was a quote
自己置于一个“
unquote scarce commodity if you if you
稀缺”的环境中——如果你从
want to look at it in economic terms
经济学的角度来看，她就是“稀缺”的，而她也确实这么做了。
what she did and she met incredible
她遇到了很多很棒的
people now did she have romantic uh
人。她和这些人之间有浪漫的
connection there no but she walked out
邂逅吗？没有。但她结识了
of there with two friends that she's
两个朋友，而且
kept in touch with you know for a year
一年多来一直保持联系。
plus so think about where your interest
所以，想想你的兴趣在哪里，想想
lie but where you can step out and be
你可以在哪里脱颖而出，展现
different where you could be unique you
你的独特之处。你
can do that in every aspect of your life
可以在生活的方方面面做到这一点。
is to being able to do that
能够做到这一点的根本驱动力
is
是
self-esteem because the higher
自尊，因为
self-esteem you have the less external
自尊越高，你就越不需要外部
validation you need unless you need to
认可，除非你需要
conform to the environment exactly even
迎合环境。甚至
there's some great studies that show
有一些很棒的研究表明，
that the higher self-esteem you have the
自尊越高，你就越
less you need to have someone who's
不需要一个
traditionally
传统意义上的“有
attractive interesting yeah because you
吸引力”的人。这很有意思，因为你会
start to see all of the value all all
开始看到一个人身上所有
the beautiful nature and behaviors of
美好的品质、行为和外在特征，
and physicality of someone and you don't
你不需要
need to walk down the street and have
走在街上让
everyone say he looks like he he's so
每个人都说“他看起来真
beautiful or she's so beautiful you know
漂亮”或“她真漂亮”，你知道
you have value in that person so
你在这个人身上看到了价值。
therefore you know and and so high
因此，你知道，高
self-esteem is indicative of so many
自尊反映了
aspects of our life and you could show
我们生活的方方面面，
up get that premium effect if you have
如果你有
high self-esteem I've never heard anyone
高自尊，你就能展现出那种优越感。我以前从未听人
talk about this before and that is so
谈论过这一点，这很
interesting cuz I I was every time I
有意思，因为我每次
hear an idea I think all at home
听到一个观点时，我都会想，所有在家听的人
everyone listening to this will kind of
都会用
they know and people they know and I and
他们认识的朋友和人来验证这个概念。就
everybody I know the people that are
我认识的所有人而言……
typically lower self-esteem are those
通常来说，自尊心较低的人往往
that are most focused on appearances and
最注重外表。
looks in fact there's one of my friends
事实上，我有个朋友，有
who when he he called me one day in the
一天在健身房打电话给我，
gym and said I'm not sure about his
说他不太确定自己
current partner um and I like why what's
现在的伴侣怎么样。我问他怎么了，他说：“
up he goes you know like when I walk
你知道，就像我挽着
into a restaurant with her on my arm I
她走进餐厅，我不
just don't know how it looks literally
知道这样看起来怎么样。”
that's what what he said to me and I
他就是这么跟我说的。我
remember having the conversation with
记得当时我和
him like bro you are screwed if that's
他聊过，我说：“兄弟，如果
what you're judging this individual
你仅仅因为对方挽着
based on how they look on your arm yes
你的胳膊就评判她，那你可就惨了。”没错，但这其实是
but it's a but it's a consequence of his
他
own need for validation from the person
需要从伴侣那里获得认可的结果。
he's with and and then it's no surprise
然后，
that the other correlation you see is
你会发现另一个关联：
those people are proba still single
这些人很可能还是单身。
those are my still friends that are
我的朋友里就有很多单身的。那些最在意外表的人，
about that that can currently have the
往往也是
most the lowest self-esteem are also the
自尊心最低的人，他们可能因为
great people for looking at the wrong
关注点错误而错失良缘。所以，这就是
things there you go that's why we need
为什么我们需要先让
ourselves before we go out there because
自己变得优秀，然后再去追求爱情。 走出去，
because think if if he was able to just
想想如果他能
take a breather work on his self-esteem
喘口气，提升一下自尊心，
there's so many things you could do
你可以做很多事情来
boost your self-esteem think of how
增强自尊心。想想
incredible his next relationship would
他的下一段恋情会有多么美好。
be facts yeah yeah self-esteem is is
没错，自尊心真的很重要，它被
underrated that's so interesting this
低估了。这个想法很有意思：
idea that when we have low self-esteem
当我们自卑的时候，我们
will care more about how the person
会更在意对方的外表，
looks because they
因为
are we believe that they can boost our
我们相信，只要和他们在一起，就能提升我们的
self-esteem by just being next to them
自尊心。
that's crazy yeah and well more so we
这太疯狂了。而且，我们
believe that Society accepts them and we
相信社会会接受他们，我们
won't be shamed by society as a result
不会因为和他们在一起而感到羞耻，对吧？
of being with them right because we want
因为
the validation from society when we have
当我们自卑的时候，我们渴望得到社会的认可。
low self-esteem but if you have high
但如果你
self-esteem you say you know what this
自尊心高，你会说：“你知道吗？这
is my partner and I don't care what you
是我的伴侣，我不在乎你怎么想，你怎么
think it doesn't matter what you think
想都不重要，
I'm happy then you can walk down the
我很快乐。”然后你就可以
street with
和
anyone and if you encountered in your
任何人一起走在街上。如果你以前做媒的时候遇到一个自卑的
someone who was low self-esteem what
人，你会怎么做？
would you suggest them to do would it
你建议他们做什么？是接受
would it be therapy would was there
治疗吗？还是说他们
something small they could do in their
可以在
life a first step they could take yeah I
生活中做一些力所能及的小事，迈出第一步？是的，我的
mean so so what we would do with the
意思是，我们
agency is we would not even start
机构的做法是，在进行数月甚至数月的辅导之前，我们甚至不会开始为
matchmaking them until we went through
他们匹配对象。
right now what are some things that you
现在，你
could do practical things you could do
可以做一些实际的事情，
it's about practicing self-compassion is
比如练习自我关怀，这是
a great way to boost self-esteem so that
提升自尊的好方法。这可以是写
could be journaling that could be
日记、
meditating that could be exercising it
冥想、锻炼等等。
also is about setting goals achievable
设定可实现的
goals and accomplishing those goals that
目标并完成这些目标也
helps to boost your self-esteem on the
有助于提升自尊。在
pathway to mastering something boosts
掌握某项技能的过程中，提升自尊也能增强
self-esteem for example
自尊。例如，在
during lockdown I started learning the
疫情封锁期间，我开始学习
the piano right just started learning it
钢琴，就是刚开始学。当
and once I got to phase two of my little
我学到我的
piano you know at home tutorial I got a
家庭钢琴教程的第二阶段时，我感觉自己更有信心了。
little boost okay I can do a little
好吧，我可以做一些
thing and then I played uh Wang Clan
小事了。然后我弹奏了王氏乐队的《
casuales everything around me I did
Everything Around Me》，我
cream on my piano and just doing
在钢琴上弹奏了《Cream》，仅仅是这样做就能
that boost self-esteem right so the
提升自尊。所以，掌握一些小事，培养
small self-compassion surrounding
自我关怀，让
yourself with other people who have
自己被其他有……的人包围，这都能提升自尊。
self-esteem High self-esteem these are
自尊，高自尊，以下是
some basic ways to help to boost it I I
一些提升自尊的基本方法。我一直在
was thinking a lot about this and I said
思考这个问题，前
day about this idea of keeping
几天我和一个朋友谈到了信守
commitments to yourself and I think I
对自己的承诺，我想我也
was talking about it with Chris
和克里斯·威廉姆森讨论过，
we keep to ourselves when no one is
当我们在无人
watching feed into our self-image like I
监督时对自己做出的承诺会影响我们的自我认知。​​我
think some of us think that self-esteem
认为我们中的一些人认为自尊
is what we've like accomplished in Life
就是我们在生活中取得了什么成就，
or what we haven't accomplished in life
或者我们没有取得什么成就。
but if we narrow it right down and zoom
但如果我们缩小范围，聚焦到
right into like this morning I told
今天早上，我告诉
myself I was going to get out of bed at
自己
9: but I hit the snooze button now it
9点起床，但我按了贪睡按钮。现在这
seems trivial but in that one decision
看起来微不足道，但正是这一个
to not keep a commitment to yourself you
没有信守对自己承诺的决定，在
wrote a little line into this the Paul
保罗·布伦森的故事中留下了一条线索。保罗·
Brunson story which is actually an
布伦森的故事实际上是一本指导
instruction manual that governs your
你人生的指导手册。
life and this the line you wrote into
你在故事中留下的线索
that story is I'm the type of person
是：我是一个
that frequently isn't able to do what I
经常无法做自己想做的事情的人。
want to do and that's an instruction
这条线索会指导
that you then when you go to work that
你，当你去上班，
when you show up when you know you think
当你出现，当你…… 你知道，你思考
about your big Ambitions in life it's an
人生中的远大抱负，就像一条
instruction it's a line of code written
指令，一行代码，早已写入你的灵魂深处。
into who you are so I've got really
所以我最近特别
obsessed with this idea of these small
着迷于“小承诺”这个概念。
small things is they're easy to do and
小事的好处在于它们容易做到，
also easy not to do but they're also
也容易做不到。但它们之所以
easy to do but we because they're easy
容易做到，是因为它们容易
not to do and because they seem small
做不到，也因为它们看起来
and trivial we tend to overlook them so
微不足道，所以我们往往会忽略它们。所以，
this idea that like start by keeping
从坚持你
these small commitments to yourself that
对自己做出的这些小承诺开始，或许就能成为通往
big results that we're seeking
我们所追求的伟大成果的途径。
you know because we look up at these
你知道，我们仰望
these figures on Instagram and on social
Instagram和其他社交
media that are like saying earlier like
媒体上的那些人，就像我之前提到的，他们
running ultramarathons and they're
跑超级马拉松，
starting these businesses and killing
创办企业，在各行各业大放异彩，
the game and we go how the [__] did they
我们会想，他们到底是怎么做到的？
get up there it must have been one big
肯定是他们做出了一个重大
decision they made it's baby steps you
决定。但其实，要从小事做起，一步一个脚印。
know baby steps and and you said
你刚才提到了
something that I think is very important
一点，我认为这一点对自尊心非常重要，那就是要付诸
you've exercised it there's an action
行动。这
it's not just about I'm going to set my
不仅仅是“我要设定一个
goal as going to wake up at a certain
目标”那么简单。 在某个
time or going to no it's that you have
时间起床，或者去……不，关键在于你已经在
you woke up at a certain time you you
某个时间起床了，你已经坚持了下来。
you've exercised it this is the key
这才是关键所在，关键在于
piece and it is it's it's it's about all
所有这些
of those small steps it's about the
小步骤，在于这些
consistency of the small steps and I
小步骤的坚持。我
think you you've seen this in you must
想你肯定
have seen this in your life is that what
在生活中见过这种情况，它的作用在于
that does is it builds habits that you
培养习惯，
then build upon and then what you'll
然后你在此基础上不断进步。你会
notice is is that the the tasks become
注意到，任务会变得越来越
bigger and bigger and bigger but you're
大，但你仍然
able to do it because you have the
能够完成，因为你有
foundation of the smaller task I've
小任务的基础。我
often wondered if there's a generation
常常在想，是否有一代人
that are kind of trapped between how
被困在
things used to be which is you know
过去的生活方式和数字时代之间。过去，人们
meeting people in your village down at
在村子里、
church in real life and then there was
教堂里等现实生活中与人见面；而
people now meet online I wonder if
现在，大多数人都在网上认识人。我想知道是否有
there's like this generation that are
一代人
trapped in between the two where they
被困在两者之间，他们到了
were of a certain age where their
某个年龄，
everyone around them was kind of meeting
周围的人都在
um in real life they didn't manage to
现实生活中见面，而他们自己却没能
meet meet someone then the digital age
遇到合适的人。然后数字时代
exploded and it's literally like this
爆发了，情况就是这样。
vertical line up when you look at the
当你看
graphs just suddenly everyone's meeting
图表的时候，你会发现突然之间大家都在
online and they don't have the digital
网上约会，但他们缺乏数字
skills they don't have the social media
技能，没有社交媒体账号，甚至
they don't know how to like upload a
不知道怎么上传
photo yeah but their way of dating this
照片。是的，他们传统的线下
IRL way of dating is now gone out of
约会方式已经过时了，
fashion and no one's doing it yeah and
没人再用了。
they would roughly be if I had to Hazard
如果让我
a guess at their age they're
猜他们的年龄，
probably
大概在
35 yeah plus now 35 Plus but it's it's
35岁以上吧。是的，现在35岁以上了，但真正
45 are are getting hit and the reason
受影响的是50岁以上的人，或者应该说是45岁以上的人。原因
why is is exactly what you're saying but
正如你所说。
then what's happened is so the number
现在的情况是，
one age of new daters in the world is
全球新约会者中人数最多的是
age 18 right we see this on the dating
18岁，我们在约会软件上就能看到这一点。18岁的
apps 18 people download the dating apps
人下载约会软件，开始
they're out on the dating scene but you
约会。但你
know what the number two age range is
知道第二大年龄段是谁吗？
well I know because you said it for 5
我知道，因为你提到了5岁。原因在于
emptiness syndrome ah you and your
空虚综合症。你和你的
partner you've had two children they go
伴侣有了两个孩子，他们去上
off to University you look and you say I
大学了，你看着他们，然后…… 你说你根本
don't even know you anymore I don't know
不认识我了，我真的不认识
you so peace I'm gone and then you break
你了，所以，拜拜，我走了。然后你们
up and then you reenter the dating
分手了，然后你又重新进入约会
market and you're like oh my God we we
市场，你会想：天哪，
didn't have dating apps when I was doing
我以前约会的时候可没有约会软件啊！
this and you're completely confused as
你完全不知道该
to what to do but I'm going to tell you
怎么办。但我要告诉你一件很
something Wild and that is is they end
神奇的事：他们最终往往都
up doing quite
做得
well you know why because they show up
很好。你知道为什么吗？因为他们展现的是
as their authentic self what we've what
真实的自己。
we've been learning I think on social
我们长期以来在社交
media for so long is you know create
媒体上学到的，就是打造一个
representative yeah you go to 80% maybe
代表形象。没错，你去看看，80%
even 90% of folks Instagram it's just
甚至90%的人在Instagram上发的都是
their representative it's it's it's not
他们的代表，那不是他们自己，对吧？
them right and so on these dating apps
在这些约会软件上也是如此。
lot of these people who have never used
很多以前从没用过约会
an app before they go online they're
软件的人，上网后会
they they they write down the imperfect
写下并不完美的
profile they they they write they talk
个人资料，他们会写，会说他们
about their what they're scared of what
害怕什么，他们的
what their fears are their
恐惧，他们的
vulnerabilities they post the photos
弱点，他们会发布
without filters right because they don't
没有滤镜的照片，因为他们
even know how to use a filter and you
甚至不知道怎么用滤镜。你会
think they're going to not do well and
想： 他们一开始表现不佳，但
they end up doing extraordinarily well
最终却取得了非凡的成就，
because they show up as their authentic
因为他们展现了真实的
self what the data is showing us more
自我。数据比以往任何时候都更加清晰地表明，
authenticity is what wins leaning into
真实才是制胜之道。拥抱
your quirks leaning into the things that
你的个性，拥抱那些
make you
让你
extraordinary you know I I I I say this
与众不同的特质。你知道吗？我
all the time to to to people who I've
经常对我
coached and that is is that think about
指导过的人说这句话：想想
you right there have been billions of
你自己，在你之前，数十亿
people who have walked this planet
人曾生活在这个星球上，
before you but no one ever walked this
但没有人拥有和
Earth with the same experiences as you
你一样的经历
or the same skills and guess what right
或技能。猜猜看，
now 8 billion people in the world no one
现在世界上有80亿人，没有人像
sees the world exactly like you see it
你一样看待世界，
no one has your skills no one looks
没有人拥有你的技能，没有人长得和你一模一样。
gets even better because no one who will
更棒的是，未来
ever live on this planet will ever look
在这个星球上，没有人会长得和你一模一样，
precisely like you talk precisely like
说话方式和你一样，看待
you see the world precisely like you so
世界的方式也和你一模一样。
therefore guess what you are
所以，猜猜看，你是
extraordinary you are truly special you
非凡的，你是真正特别的，你是
are truly unique there's no one ever
真正独一无二的，没有人会像你一样。
like you so if you only that you win
所以，如果你仅仅拥有这一点，你就能成功。
what if I'm an [__] you
如果我是个混蛋呢？
you well well you know what see are you
你知道吗？你是个
a narcissistic psychopath [__] like
自恋的心理变态者。
you know what I mean like if you if you
你知道我的意思，就像混蛋一样，如果你
if you don't like who you are you don't
不喜欢真实的自己，不想把真实的自己
want to put that out there you want to
展现出来，你想过滤一下，修饰一下，对，
it yeah trim it cut it expand it I'm
修剪一下，删减一下，扩展一下。我懂
with you I'm with you so yes many of us
你，我懂你。所以，是的，我们很多人
don't like you know various parts of who
都不喜欢…… 我们自身有很多方面，
we are the key is to embrace the good
关键在于接纳好的一面。
but going back to Carol riffs six
但回到卡罗尔·里夫斯提出的
dimensions of psychological well-being
心理健康六个维度，
self-acceptance is to say you know what
自我接纳意味着，你知道，
these three things I do yeah [__] do
这三件事我做了，没错，混蛋们会做
those three things but do I lay that out
这三件事，但我会坦诚相告吗？
no well here's what you in a dating app
不会。好吧，在约会
no in a dating app you lay out what it
软件上，你会怎么做？在约会软件上，你会坦诚地表达
is that you desire what it is that you
你的渴望和
are seeking but are you transparent
追求。但当
about those things when you're
你
interacting with them absolutely you're
与对方互动时，你会
transparent because if those [__]
坦诚地表达这些吗？当然会。因为如果你身上有这些混蛋的
traits are part of you it's going to
特质，它们就会
show up in your Behavior so you alert
体现在你的行为中。所以你要
the person ahead of time I'm working on
提前告知对方，我正在努力改正
these things I don't want to scare them
这些缺点，我不想吓跑他们。
off no you don't but you want to be your
你当然不想，但你想做
true self but it depends on on what kind
真实的自己。但这取决于
of trait we're talking about though so I
我们谈论的是哪种特质。我的
mean you'd have to give me example okay
意思是，你得给我举个例子。好吧，
I'll give you an example I um this is
我给你举个例子。嗯，
I'm playing a role here okay so people
我在这里扮演一个角色。这样人们
don't clip this and put it on the
就不会把这段剪辑下来放到
internet but say that I had a toxic
网上，而是说我身上有一种有害的
trait where I get Ultra needy and I'm
特质。 我特别粘人，而且特别容易
like very jealous and I'm very easily
嫉妒，很容易被
tricked by anything that makes me feel
任何让我觉得
like you're cheating on me or you're you
你背叛我的事情骗到，或者你
know I'm like insecure from like maybe
知道，我缺乏安全感，可能是因为
was younger or whatever okay this is
小时候发生过什么事之类的。好吧，这
good A lot of people have this so you'd
很好，很多人都有这种感觉，所以你会
be very anxious the sounds very uh
很焦虑。这听起来很像
typical of of of an anxious uh
典型的焦虑型
attachment style so the question is is
依恋模式。问题是，
are you working on it because if you're
你在努力克服这个问题吗？如果
if you're working on that and you
你在努力，并且
acknowledge that that's someone that
承认自己是这样的人，那你们的
that's a great relationship to be in cuz
关系就很好，因为
someone is proactively working on their
对方在积极地处理自己的
truma
创伤。
but if you tell me this is how I am and
但如果你告诉我我就是这样，却什么
I'm doing nothing about it well that's a
都不做，那就有
problem I want this relationship so I
问题了。我想要这段关系，所以我
can work on it with you no well the best
可以和你一起努力。不，解决这段关系的最佳
time to work on this relationship is
时机是在
before you're in it
你们开始这段关系之前。
goodbye that's pretty much what it is
再见，差不多就是这样。
and and but but you know what those are
你知道吗，这些才是
the type of conversations that we should
我们应该讨论的问题：在开始这段
the relationship so say in that case of
关系之前，我该如何解决这些问题？ 缺乏
insecure jealous anxious type does that
安全感、嫉妒、焦虑，这是否
mean like going to therapy and you when
意味着你需要接受心理治疗？
you say working on it yeah okay great
你说要努力克服这些问题，嗯，问得好。
question so let's first say this about
首先，关于
therapy I have tons of friends who are
心理治疗，我有很多朋友是
some of the top therapists in the world
世界顶尖的心理治疗师，他们都很
love it but when you look at the
喜欢心理治疗。但是，如果你看看
satisfaction rate that most people
大多数人对心理治疗的满意度，
report going to therapists very low very
就会发现非常低，非常
low if you look at the access to
低。而且，找到心理
therapists or top therapists very hard
治疗师，尤其是顶尖的心理治疗师，非常困难，
to get access so most people cannot go
所以大多数人都无法获得治疗。
so I'm I'm consciously always saying
因此，我总是强调，
okay it's important to be able to go if
如果
you can but most of this work you have
可以的话，去接受治疗固然重要，但大部分的功课你必须自己完成。
to do on your on your own first part is
首先，我这么说
and this is not me to be self- serving
并不是想自我推销，
here but I think podcasts are incredible
但我认为播客
in creating awareness but I will say on
在提高人们的意识方面非常有效。说
this particular podcast quite honestly
实话，在这个播客里，
you've had all of the greats within this
你们请到了这个
space all of the greats from we talked
领域的所有大师，从我们之前提到的
about Dr waldinger to uh Gabor mate like
瓦尔丁格博士到加博尔·马特，
you've had all of the greats who will
所有大师都曾来过，他们会让
give you a taste of what you need to
你初步了解你需要做些什么来
create that awareness and then you dig
建立这种意识。然后，你可以
deeper you purchase the book yeah you
深入挖掘，购买书籍。
purchase the book and then you do the
买下这本书，然后按照
work in the book Gabor mate all the time
书里的练习去做。加博尔总是
he talks about you know what you you
说你应该做什么，比如
should do let's meditate let's Journal
冥想、写日记，
like he prescribes he sets it out but a
就像他建议的那样。但他已经明确指出了。但
lot of us don't want to do that level of
我们很多人都不愿意进行这种程度的
Investigation no way we want quick easy
探索，我们只想速战速决，追求简单快捷。
and now and now yeah but guess what
但是，
flourishing if that's all you desire
如果你只想要这些，你永远也达不到那种蓬勃发展的境界。平庸很普遍，应该
should I say is common the moment that
说，平庸本身就很普遍。
mediocre in society today you typically
在当今社会，一旦你能超越平庸，你通常就会被人
are seen that's how low the bar is it's
瞧不起，这就是社会标准低到什么程度的原因。
the same way in relationships but it's
人际关系也是如此，
that you have with yourself if you do
你与自己的关系也是如此。如果你付出
any bit of work you become a
一点努力，你就会变得更好，
exceptionally better for you for your
对你、对你的
partner just just a little bit of work
伴侣都更有益。只需要一点点努力，
learn to act actively listen learn to
学会积极行动，学会倾听，学会
learn to just simply
简单地
respond which is active listening versus
回应——也就是积极倾听而不是被动
reacting that's a game changer it's this
反应。这会彻底改变一切。就是这样，就是这样。
it's this there's this idea of like
还有一种叫做元
metacognition which is thinking about
认知的概念，就是思考
your thinking and when me and my partner
你的思考过程。 我和伴侣
have a disagreement now I it's almost
现在有点分歧，我感觉自己好像
like I now have this metacognition it's
有了某种元认知能力，就像
like I'm I'm watching the situation
我在观察和分析整个情况，然后把它看得
anding the situation and makes such a
特别
big deal my girlfriend was saying
严重。
something to me the other day and in my
前几天我女朋友跟我说了些什么，
head I'm going think about how you're
我脑子里就一直在想：你该怎么
listening make sure you're listening
听？确保你认真听，
intently make sure she feels Hur that's
确保她能感受到……
what my brain is saying now yeah that's
嗯，这就是我现在脑子里的想法。
it but before it was all like
但以前我满脑子想的都是：该死，
[__] I need to let her know how she's
我得让她知道她
wrong yeah but see this is the work yeah
错在哪儿。是啊，但这就是努力的意义所在，这就是
this is the work that we were talking
我们之前讨论的，
about that you were doing that is work
你一直在做的，这就是努力的意义所在。是
yeah but it's paying dividends it's like
啊，但它会带来回报，
the return on investment on learning the
学习这些技能的投资回报率
skills is infinite it's because I'm sure
是无限的。因为我相信
you take that into your business you
你会把这些运用到你的事业中，运用到你的
take that into uh social situations
社交场合中。
active listening stepping outside of
积极倾听，跳出
yourself the the the these skills change
自己的视角，这些技能会改变
your life and to go back to Dr
你的人生。回到
waldinger's work is when you're able to
瓦尔丁格博士的研究，当你能够
make these small adjustments in your
在生活中做出这些小的调整时，
life you're happier less stress you live
你会更快乐，压力更小，寿命
longer you make more money the the
更长，收入更高。
rewards are infinite this old the
回报无穷无尽。
generation that we said we think might
我们之前说过，这一代人可能
be trapped a little bit in a
有点被困在
technological transition one of the
技术转型中。
things my friends that are part of that
我的朋友中就有人
generation say to me is that there's
跟我说，现在
just no people left anymore and one of
人太少了。我的一个
my friends has actually said to me a few
朋友甚至跟我说过好
times that she needs to put herself in a
几次，她需要让自己置身于有
situation where she's going to meet lots
很多男性的环境中。
gets particularly annoyed when her
当她的
friendship group don't want to go to the
朋友们都成双成对地不想去那种
places cuz they're all paired off okay
地方时，她尤其感到恼火。
where where they don't want to go to to
他们不想去那种有
an envir where there's lots of men does
很多男性的环境。
it matter you talk about this in chapter
你在第四章会谈到
4 the importance of the sex ratio yes
性别比例的重要性，是的，这很重要。
yeah does it matter so sex ratio is huge
性别比例非常重要。
the best example of sex ratio is look at
性别比例最好的例子就是看看
China where you had the basically the
中国农村地区的情况，
one child policy where you see a heavy
那里曾经实行独生子女政策，
number of men so the sex ratio is the
男性数量非常多。性别比例是指
number of uh women to men right and so
女性与男性的数量比。
you look look at the number of men
看看
women in in in China especially in the
中国，尤其是农村地区，男性数量远远多于女性。
farm area of China so what what does
中国的农业地区，这
that mean what that means is that women
意味着什么？这意味着女性
now have more negotiation power with the
现在拥有了更大的谈判筹码。
men if you go back 40 years you'd have
如果你回到40年前，
to be buried off by 18 17 16 in some of
在某些地区，你18岁、17岁、16岁就得被埋葬，
those areas you would have no say as to
你对
who you could now I literally just read
你的伴侣没有任何发言权。而现在，我刚刚读到
an article where you have 30 plus year
一篇文章，里面提到一些30多岁的
old women going into those areas saying
女性进入这些地区，说“
we choose whoever we want out here you
我们想找谁就找谁，
know we can do whatever we want you have
我们想做什么就做什么”，她们拥有了
more negotiation power but that also
更大的谈判筹码。但这也会
impacts the relationships that then do
影响到之后
form for example look at most University
形成的人际关系。例如，看看现在大多数大学
campuses that now have majority women at
校园，女生占多数，校园里的
in terms of sex at the
性生活简直爆棚。
campuses off the charts why because you
为什么？因为
have a small pool of men who say you
只有少数男性会说：“
know what we now have negotiation power
我们现在有谈判筹码了，
there there there's few of us there's
我们人少，而
all these women out here and and and
外面有这么多女人。”结果就是，
what's what's happening is the women are
女性
looking at the small pool of men and
看着这少数男性，
saying okay we only have access to these
心想“好吧，我们只能接触到这些
guys the guys know okay we have access
男人”，而男人们知道“好吧，我们能接触
to all of these women so therefore we're
到这么多女人”，所以她们
going to act a fool you know and what
就“放纵自己”，结果呢？
ends up happening is you end you end up
最终你会
seeing how
发现，
relationships change the formation
人际关系会随着
changes based on sex ratio so looking at
性别比例的变化而改变，这种改变会影响人际关系的形成。从
some of these macroecon omic you can see
一些宏观经济角度来看，你可以看到性别比例
how it does impact how a relationship is
如何影响人际关系的
formed and then what happens in the
形成以及
relationship there's some environments
关系的发展。有些环境
that are and there's some professions
和职业
that are typically dominated by one
通常由某一
gender typically for whatever reason in
性别主导，这通常是由于
the book you talk about like engineering
你在书中提到的原因，比如工程
degree courses yes so if I was a woman
学位课程。是的，如果我是一个女人，比如
and I would say I was just you know I
我
was 20 years old and I was desperate to
20岁，非常渴望
find a man going into a engineering
找到一个男人，那么选择工程学位课程
degree course would put Leverage on my
会让我更有优势。
side yes it's just something to think
是的，这值得思考。
about you know people choosing jobs and
人们在选择工作和
environments to work in if they are
工作环境时，如果他们
really trying to expose themselves to a
真的想让自己置身于一个
gender balance that's in their favor
性别比例对他们有利的环境，那么
we're talking about heterosexual
我们这里讨论的是异性
heterosexual couples here then that is
恋伴侣，这确实是一个需要
something to consider it it is but even
考虑的因素。但即使是这一点也存在
that point is controversial right
争议，对吧？
because that point that you just
因为你刚才提到的这一点（顺便说一句，
mentioned which I endorse by the way
我赞同这一点），我
then I'll cut it
就不多说了，
out it's all controversial no but but
它本身就很有争议。但
the reason why I say that point is
我之所以说这一点
controversial but I love it is because
有争议，但我喜欢它，是因为
what you're saying is you're saying hey
你说的…… 你是说，嘿，
young lady you're going off you're
年轻的女士，你正在努力，你在
thinking about your career also start
考虑你的事业，同时也要开始
thinking about your long-term partner at
考虑你的长期伴侣。
the same time I I feel as if a large
我觉得
narrative that's placed on us in Western
西方社会强加给我们的很大一种观念是：先把
Society is knock out the education and
教育和事业搞定，把这些都安排
up nicely now you could focus on these
妥当之后，你才能专注于
other things in life I have sat at the
生活中的其他事情。我
deathbed of two people in my life I will
一生中曾两次坐在两个人的床边，我永远不会
never forget these moments ever what
忘记这些时刻。
they did is they both said the same
他们都说了同样的话。
things these were you know two different
你知道，这是两个不同的
people different times they both died
人，不同的时间，他们都在
within 24 hours of me seeing them they
我见到他们后的24小时内去世了。他们都说了同样的话：
said this thing life it goes by fast
生命转瞬即逝。
goes by fast the second thing is they
第二件事是，他们
begin recounting the the intimate
开始回忆与
relationships that they had with all of
所有
their with with their loved ones you
爱人的亲密关系。你
know they're they're they're
知道，他们在
recollecting this now there's other
回忆这些。当然，
things that they'll talk about certain
他们也会谈到其他事情，比如一些
regrets wanting to be happier wanting to
遗憾，想要更快乐，想要
have done certain things but ultimately
做某些事情，但最终，他们都会说：
it's about I remember the good times
我记住了与
with the people I love the most so
我最爱的人共度的美好时光。所以，这对
what's interesting to me about that is
我来说很有意思。
there's no talk about their career
没人谈论他们的事业，
there's no talk about what they
没人谈论他们在
accomplished professionally there's no
专业领域取得的成就，也没人
talk about
谈论
what they learned in school so does that
他们在学校学到的东西。那么，这是否
then mean that the most important facets
意味着我们生活中最重要的方面
of our life are the relationships that
是
we form I I would say yes and then if
我们建立的人际关系呢？我会说是的。如果是这样，
that's the case why don't we focus on
为什么我们不
those things earlier let's focus on that
早点关注这些事情呢？让我们关注一下吧。这就是
that's the reason why I love that
我喜欢这
statement because yes you know I my my
句话的原因，因为你知道，我的
sons are 10 and 13 already I'm like look
儿子们已经10岁和13岁了，我会说，听着，
let's talk about your partners let's
让我们谈谈你的伴侣，
talk about how you're going to go about
谈谈你打算怎么
doing this because ultimately that will
做，因为最终这将
be the most important decision that you
是你人生中最重要的决定。
make in life so let's talk about kids
所以我们来谈谈孩子
and dating them we talked about Boomers
和与他们约会吧。我们
a little bit there's this word in your
稍微谈到了婴儿潮一代。你的
book pronounced
书中有一个词，发音是“
hyper gamey yeah hypergamy that's
hyper gamey”，没错，就是“hypergamy”，也就是“
hypergamy seeking partners of higher
hypergamy”，寻找
Social Status is notable in online
社会地位更高的伴侣，这在网络约会中很常见。
dating what is what is hyper game me
什么是“hyper game”？是的，是的，是的。
yeah yeah yeah and and I want to talk
我想谈谈
about genz because you said a statement
Z世代，因为你在
at the start of this conversation about
这次谈话开始时说过他们是……
them being the most successful in
在婚姻中最成功的，
marriages in your full costing yes yes
你的全部成本是，是的，
okay so all right hypergamy is a topic
好的，所以，高嫁择偶是一个经常
that gets a lot of push back but it is
受到质疑的话题，但事实就是如此，
can't we we cannot um disagree with all
我们不能否认所有
of the data and what the and what that
数据及其所
suggests is essentially someone who is
表明的内容。本质上，高嫁择偶是指
Seeking a partner of equal or greater
寻找与自己资源相当或更高的伴侣，
resources men and women well it's it's
无论男女。
it's it's it's always categorized as
这通常被归类为
heterosexual women okay
异性恋女性
seeking a heterosexual man of equal or
寻找与自己资源相当或更高的异性恋男性。
typically people point to is when they
人们通常引用的数据是
look at um degrees college degrees and
大学学历，以及
they look at women in in in online
在线
dating so they say okay let's look at um
约会中的女性。他们会说，好的，让我们看看
women in online dating across different
不同
dating apps and we'll look at all of
约会应用程序上的在线女性，看看所有
those with a college degree who is it
拥有大学学历的女性，
that they typically swipe right on or
她们通常会右滑谁，或者
who is it that they typically select and
她们通常会选择谁？
on average it's men who have at least a
平均而言，是至少拥有
college degree or greater master's
大学学历或更高学历（硕士学位）的男性。
whole push back that I think ends up
我认为最终
happening is you see people say well
出现的反对意见是，人们会说，瞧，
there it is right there these women are
这些女人
all opportunists that's what they're
都是机会主义者，她们就是这样。
looking for they're looking for
她们在寻找
opportunity and I say oh hold on for a
机会，我说，等等，
second do you realize first that for
你有没有意识到，
hundreds of thousands of years this was
几十万年来，这就是社会
the structure this was the only
结构，这是
structure you needed we've talked about
你唯一需要的结构？我们之前讨论过，
it you must have chosen if you a woman
如果你是女性，
you must have chosen a partner that had
你必须选择一个拥有
equal or greater resources if you wanted
同等或更优资源的伴侣，才能
survive to next week so why is it still
活到下周。那么，为什么这种结构仍然存在，
here or next year well you know why
甚至明年仍然存在呢？你知道为什么吗？
because the patriarchy has not been
因为父权制并没有被
destroyed it it is it has not been
摧毁，它并没有被
destabilized it's because modern
瓦解。这是因为现代
relationships these relationships around
关系，这些围绕
self-expression just started in
自我表达的关系，直到
1960 I mean I I think it's it is
1960年才开始出现。我的意思是，我认为，
fascinating to think that women just
女性才刚刚
began to have choice and remember we're
开始拥有选择权，这很令人着迷。记住，我们
talking about these weird Western IND
谈论的是这些奇怪的西方独立、受过教育、
educated industrialized right Rich
工业化、富裕的
democratic nations have just begun to
民主国家，它们才刚刚开始
have a bit of choice you know what I
拥有一些选择权，你知道我的
mean a bit of choice just now so
意思吗？只是现在才开始拥有一些选择权。
therefore we're living in a day and age
因此，我们生活在一个你无法反驳的时代。
against this you know you you when I say
你知道，我说
you can't argue against it is is you
你无法反驳的意思是，你
have to understand why that is but the
必须理解为什么会这样。但
reason why I say I believe that gen Z
我之所以这么说，是因为我相信……  Z世代的
will have the strongest marriages is I
婚姻会最牢固，但我
also think they'll have the fewest
认为他们的
marriages of any
婚姻数量也会是所有世代中最少的。
decline without question you can't argue
毫无疑问，婚姻正在衰落，这一点毋庸置疑。
cannot argue it's on the decline but
但
what we're going to see is we're going
我们将会看到，只有
to see a small percentage of people who
一小部分人
decide to join in Union in what we're
选择缔结我们
today calling marriage and they will
今天所说的婚姻，他们的婚姻会
have exceptionally strong marriages
异常牢固，
because they'll have consciously chosen
因为他们是经过深思熟虑才选择
to go into this Union they'll have the
进入婚姻的。他们拥有所需的
tools and they'll help each other to you
工具，并且会互相帮助，共同
know to to self-evolve so and less kids
成长。所以，
they'll have less kids yeah are you
他们的孩子会更少。是的，你
concerned about that the sort of decline
担心生育率下降吗？
of people having kids I'm I'm quite
我非常
aware of of of some of this data right
了解一些相关数据，比如人口更替率，
and this replacement rate this rate of
也就是
us not having enough children to meet
我们生育的孩子数量不足以满足人口
the replacement rate which I think on
更替率的情况。我认为平均而言，人口更替率
average is typically like 2.1 right so
通常是2.1左右。
you think that in the United States or
你认为在美国、
in the UK in Japan where I know this is
英国、日本（我知道日本的情况非常
this is hitting heavy uh really all
严重）以及
throughout most of the world but I want
世界上大部分地区，这种情况会持续下去吗？我想说的是，
to get to where it's not happening but
这种情况并没有发生。
through most of the world what you have
世界上的现状
is you have people not having enough
是，人们生育的
children to meet the replacement rate
孩子数量不足以满足人口更替率。人口
what's the replacement rate so that is
更替率是指
happen in order to replace the Aging
为了补充老龄化和
dying population ah okay so typically
死亡人口，需要出生的新生儿数量。通常情况下，这个数字
it's it's like it's 2.1 right uh but
是2.1，对吧？但是，
we're not couples are getting together
夫妻们并没有生育足够的孩子，
they're having 1.8 you know or one or
他们平均每个家庭只生1.8个，或者
one or whatever it may be
一个，或者其他什么数字。
now what that means is it means
这意味着，正如
precisely what you said and that is is
你所说，
that we will have an older population
我们将面临人口老龄化的问题。而人口老龄化会导致
population we won't be able to do all
我们无法满足老年人的所有
the things that we need for that older
需求。
population think about the tax base
想想看，
who's going to support the older
谁来承担老年人的税收和生活开支？谁来
in the nursing homes to support an older
养老院照顾
population or who's going to be at home
老年人？谁来居家养老？
or and so the
所以，
underpopulation is I believe it is a
我认为人口不足是一个
real issue however it gets very
真正的问题，而且这个问题非常政治化。我认为它之所以
gets political and I've seen uh have you
会政治化，是因为我听说过……你
heard of uh Neo natalism no in natalism
听说过新生育主义吗？不，是新生育主义。
right was that uh so it is when you
嗯，当你
begin to look at
开始
underpopulation based on nationality or
根据国籍或
ethnicity and when you you begin to look
种族来看待人口不足的问题时，当你深入观察时，
deeper you say hold on for a second the
你会说，等等，
world is beginning to slowly become
世界正在慢慢地变得
underpopulated but if you look at
人口不足。但如果你看看
Nigeria yeah it's going off it's going
尼日利亚，是的，那里的人口正在迅速增长，真的在增长。
off I have no Nigerian friend that
我认识的尼日利亚朋友，几乎每个人都有
doesn't have like eight 10 brothers and
八到十个兄弟
sisters you know and like to this day
姐妹，你知道吗？直到今天都是如此。而且，
and if you look at it's not just Nigeria
不仅仅是尼日利亚，
like you look at West Africa you look at
看看西非，看看那些
different pockets of mostly what's
主要被
considered to be black populations Brown
认为是黑人或棕色人种
populations
聚居区的地方，
you see that the
你会发现那里的
population is growing you know when I um
人口正在增长。你知道吗，
David McQueen did an exhibit here in
大卫·麦奎因在伦敦做了一个让
London that blew me away was it was at
我震撼的展览，那是在
the tape Gallery it was called the year
磁带画廊举办的，叫做“
three he took photos of every year three
三年级”。他拍摄了伦敦所有三年级班级的照片，并
hundreds of photos up in the tape
在磁带画廊里展出了成百上千张照片。
gallery and you walk in right and at
你走进去，对吧？
that time my son was year three so I
当时我儿子也上三年级，所以我
walk in and you look at this thing and
走进去，看着这些照片，
you say oh my gosh this is what London
你会说，我的天哪，这就是伦敦
future and you know what it is it's
未来的模样。你知道吗？ 那里
mostly black mostly Muslim and I think
主要是黑人，主要是穆斯林。我认为，
that what you're seeing in the natalism
在生育主义/
neo- natalism movement is you're seeing
新生育主义运动中，我们看到的是
a lot of people who are scared by that
很多人对此感到恐惧，
and they say to themselves okay what we
他们对自己说，好吧，我们
need to do is we need to figure out how
需要做的就是想办法
we can produce more offspring of a
增加
particular ethnicity or of a particular
特定种族或特定
nationality you've begun to see
国籍的后代。你已经开始看到
presidential candidates in the United
美国总统候选人
States talk about this uh it is I think
谈论这个话题了。我认为这是
an
一个
extremely
极其
dangerous category and area to to to to
危险的领域，或者说，
it's a dangerous idea to to to put
这是一个危险的想法，
forward in the future it's going to be
在未来提出来很危险。这将是
one of the top issues that that we're
我们辩论的首要议题之一，
debating because if you play that
因为如果你把这个话题推演下去，
forward not long you wouldn't have to
你
play it forward very long to realize
很快就会意识到，
that there's certain races that will be
某些种族曾经是
that will once the majority that would
多数族裔，
then become a minority race oh yeah in
现在却变成了少数族裔。是的，在
the UK it's already been predicted that
英国，已经有人预测，到
by I think it's roughly 2050 that you're
2050年左右，
than half of the population in the UK be
英国大约一半甚至更多的人口将是
black or brown I'm not talking about uh
黑人或棕色人种。 我说的不是
London I'm not talking about England I'm
伦敦，也不是英格兰，我
talking about in the UK that to me is
说的是整个英国。对我来说，这
absolutely it's mind-blowing it's
简直太不可思议了，
mind-blowing to think about that and
想想都觉得不可思议。
when some people think about that
有些人想到这一点会感到
they're excited by by by by that future
兴奋，对未来充满憧憬，觉得
they're saying okay this is wonderful
这太棒了。
but there are other people who hear that
但也有人听到这话会
and they become very scared and that
感到非常害怕，
fear I think is facilitating a lot of
我认为正是这种恐惧助长了许多
these more extreme ideas that are very
极端且非常危险的想法。是
isn't this cool every single
不是很酷？
conversation I have here on the DI ofo
我在DI ofo上的每一期节目
at the very end of it you'll know I
最后都会
asked the guest to leave a question in
请嘉宾在“CEO日记”里留下一个问题。
is we've turned every single question
我们把“CEO日记”里的每一个问题都做成了
conversation cards that you can play at
对话卡片，你可以在
home so you've got every guest we've
家里玩。卡片上包含了我们收到的每一位嘉宾的问题，
of it if you scan that QR code you get
扫描卡片背面的二维码，就能
to watch the person who answered that
看到回答这个
question we're finally revealing all of
问题的人。现在，我们终于要公布所有的
the questions and the people that
问题和
answered the question the brand new
回答者了！全新
version 2 updated conversation cards are
升级的第二版对话卡片已经
out right now at Theon conversation
上线！ 现在，在Theon conversation
cards.com as you'll know if you've
cards.com网站上，正如你
listened to this podcast before I'm an
之前听过这个播客的人所知，我是
investor in a company called hu I'm on
一家名为hu的公司的投资人，也是
their board and they sponsor this
他们的董事会成员，他们赞助了这个
podcast Daily Greens which is this
播客。
powder I have in front of me for those
我面前的这款Daily Greens粉末，正如
of you that can see that gives you some
你所看到的，它能给你带来令人
incredible health benefits your energy
难以置信的健康益处，提升
your concentration your immunity is now
你的精力、注意力和免疫力。这款粉末富含
available in the UK for the 91 vitamins
91种维生素
and minerals you get from it the
和矿物质，以及适应原和
adaptogens the daily green probiotics
Daily Green益生菌，现在已在英国上市。
last year or so all of you on this
过去一年左右的时间里，所有在这个
podcast that have dm'd me about this
播客上私信我
product have asked when it will be
询问这款产品何时会
coming to the UK it's now here if you're
在英国发售的听众，现在它终于来了！如果你
someone that wants to get more greens
想在饮食中增加更多绿色蔬菜，
into your diet then I highly recommend
我强烈推荐你尝试一下。它
giving it a go not only is it good for
不仅对
you but it tastes good win-win the
你有益，而且味道也很好，绝对物超所值。这款
product was so popular in the US that
产品在美国非常受欢迎，
it's sold out over and over again and I
经常售罄，我
think that's what's going to happen here
认为
in the UK so get your hands on it now
在英国也会如此。所以，赶紧入手吧！
just give it a try take a picture tag me
试试看，拍张照片，标记我，或者私
DM me let me know what you think of it
信我。 告诉我你对它的看法，
and because I think it's going to become
因为我觉得它会成为
one of your staple products if you're
你的必备品之一。如果你正在
someone that's looking for a green
寻找环保
product in your life then I really
产品，那么我真的
believe that this will probably become
相信它会像
your staple as it has become mine before
我一样成为你的必备品。 在
we get into this some of these key
我们深入探讨一些关键
questions which are really things we
问题之前，这些问题我们
talked about earlier but like what
之前也讨论过，比如
should I be looking for in a partner and
我应该在伴侣身上寻找什么，
what should I not be looking for in a
不应该寻找什么。
partner I wanted to quickly go over this
我想快速回顾一下
thing called attachment Theory because
依恋理论，因为
in our last conversation it's one of the
在我们上次的谈话中，它是被
most replayed moments from our previous
反复提及的内容之一。我在这里简要
conversation just to summarize
概括一下
attachment Theory because I think this
依恋理论，因为我认为这对于
we're going to talk about next what are
我们接下来要讨论的内容——成人
the four categories of attachments in
依恋的四种类型——至关重要。好的，
adults yeah all right so uh Mary
玛丽·
answorth is really the person that led
安斯沃斯是
us to attachment Theory she worked with
依恋理论的奠基人。她曾与
John Balby but Mary answorth really
约翰·巴尔比共事，是一位
American Canadian psychologist and let's
美国/加拿大心理学家。我们来
just talk about the the test that she
谈谈她
gave because I think it adds uh context
设计的测试，因为我认为这有助于理解。
so she essentially would take a a a
她会带一个
child and a caregiver and she would take
孩子和一个照护者，她会
this child she did this did this in
在
Baltimore of all places she would take
巴尔的摩（一个很特别的地方）带孩子和
this child in in a primary caregiver and
主要照护者一起走进一个房间，或者
and the caregiver or she would allow the
她会让
child and the caregiver to walk into a
孩子和照护者一起走进一个
room and the caregiver would leave and
房间，然后照护者……
then momentarily come back now if the
如果照护者离开，孩子会短暂地回来，然后
would be distress oh my gosh I can't
感到不安，比如“天哪，我不敢
believe this maybe there's some crying
相信”，可能会哭，可能会
maybe there there's some yelling then
喊叫。
when the caregiver comes back if the
当照护者回来时，如果
child immediately soothed okay my
孩子立刻安抚说“好了，
caregiver is back I'm okay that was
照护者回来了，我没事了”，这被
considered to be secure secure
认为是安全型
attachment now if the caregiver left and
依恋。如果照护者离开后又
came back and the child was distressed
回来，孩子在照护者离开
when the caregiver left came back and
时感到不安，照护者回来后孩子仍然
still a little distressed but okay but
有些不安，但又说“好吧，但
I'm not sure are you going to leave
我不知道你又要走了吗？
again don't leave please right the back
别走，求你了”，这种来回的
anxious attachment then the third cuz at
互动被认为是焦虑型依恋。当时有
that time there was three primary the
三种主要的依恋类型，
third was the caregiver would come back
第三种是照护者回来后，
and the child would say whatever you
孩子会说一些……你
know that was avoidant so these were the
知道的……这就是回避型依恋。以上就是
three
三种
fundamental uh attachment
基本的依恋
Styles and what her work then LED is to
类型，以及她（指拉文博士）的研究成果，
other researchers Sue Johnson Etc to
其他研究者，比如苏·约翰逊等人，将这些理论
then apply that to how we show up as
应用于我们
adults and Dr LaVine in his book
成年人的依恋模式。拉文博士在他的著作《依恋》中也
attached then starts to write about
谈到了
attachment but I want to say something
依恋，但我想说一些
very important that I've not heard
非常重要的事情，我以前从未听说过。
heard I've actually not heard anyone
我其实很少听到有人
talk about with attachment and that is
谈论依恋，而
is that we have to understand that
我们必须明白，
attachment is phenomenal in
依恋对于
understanding how we show up as adults
理解我们成年后的行为模式
and how we relate but we have to
和人际关系至关重要。但我们也必须
understand this is a very Western
意识到，这其实是一个非常西方的
concept and the reason why I say that is
概念。我这么说的原因是，
done in Uganda some small tests done in
乌干达和日本都做过一些关于依恋的小规模实验。
Japan around attachment and do you know
你知道
what happened when the care Giver in
在日本，当照护者
Japan left the the child and comes back
离开孩子后再回来时会发生什么吗？
that the child would freak out would be
孩子会非常焦虑，
under complete distress that the
因为
caregiver left and when the child came
照护者离开了。当
when the caregiver came back the child
照护者回来后，孩子仍然会感到焦虑和
stress but that was considered a secure
不安。然而，这却被认为是安全型依恋。
attachment so you think hold on for a
你可能会想，
second that same child that that would
等等，同样的孩子，如果
in the US but but that's secure in Japan
在美国，会被认为是安全型依恋吗？
why is that well the reason why is
为什么呢？原因在于，
because when you
当你
investigate how the child was reared you
调查孩子的成长经历时，你会
realize that in certain areas of the
发现，在世界上的某些地区，
world mostly collectivist or Eastern
尤其是在集体主义或东方
societies that child the that uh
社会，
caregiver typically the mother would
照护者（通常是母亲）几乎
never leave the child so therefore a
不会离开孩子。因此，
child recognized the caregiver as always
孩子始终感受到照护者的陪伴，从而形成安全型依恋。
being there always being there and so
总是陪伴在身边，所以即使
they when the caregiver came back but
照顾者回来，孩子也会感到如此痛苦。
the reason why I say this is because I
我之所以这么说，是因为我
think what ends up happening with
认为
attachment style and I've I I've seen
依恋模式最终会导致这样的结果。我见过很多不同的
different different concepts that get
概念，它们都
introduced which are very important but
非常重要，但
what we see is we always see it through
我们总是透过
this Western lens yeah we have to
西方的视角来看待它。我们必须
realize we're living in a global world
意识到，我们生活在一个全球化的世界，
right where many of us have lineage or
我们中的许多人都有
parents who are from different parts of
来自世界各地的血统或父母，
the world and so therefore we have to
因此我们必须
respect all parts and therefore um it
尊重所有文化。所以，
know that attachment style or you're
了解依恋模式、
talking about love language or whatever
爱的语言或其他任何概念都很重要，
it may be these are good
这些都是很好的
Concepts but we have to understand that
概念，但我们必须明白，
these are not globally
它们并不具有全球
applicable they're very narrow um in
适用性，在这方面它们非常狭隘。
that regard and you know we for some
你知道，不知
reason we're all drawn to these when we
何故，当只有三种依恋模式时，我们总是倾向于
just pick the one we are and then it
选择其中一种，然后它就
gives us all the answers that's makes
给了我们所有问题的答案，这让
life much easier than the complexity of
生活比面对复杂的真相要容易得多。
the truth yes so let's let's not burst
所以，我们还是别争了。
Paul we
保罗，我们
like but it's I think yeah I I relate
喜欢这种错觉，但我认为，是的，我
most to this idea of being the an ious
最能理解这种想法，那就是成为一个心不在焉、
preoccupied one who probably wouldn't
心事重重的人，他们可能根本不在乎别人什么时候
care when they came back in the room
回到房间。
sorry no I got that wrong yeah you're
抱歉，不，我搞错了。是的，你是
avoidant yes I'm avoidant yes yeah and
回避型依恋，是的，我是回避型依恋，是的，是的，但是，
but but you know what's interest okay
但是你知道什么有趣吗？好吧，
you know what um well since we're on
你知道吗？嗯，既然我们谈到了
attachment sty I've got to go here is
依恋类型，我得说，这里有
there's some phenomenal research that's
一些关于
been done around attachment style and
依恋类型和
sex right you ready for this the cameras
性行为的惊人研究。准备好了吗？摄像机，
a second cut the cameras down are they
等一下，关掉摄像机。关了吗？关掉了。
off they're off okay go ahead yeah this
好的，继续。是的，
this is some phenomen research that that
这是一项惊人的研究，它让
that that blows my mind so um these
我大开眼界。这些
researchers looked at the number of
研究人员
orgasms that people have based on their
根据人们的
attachment style and the type of sexual
依恋类型和性行为类型，观察了他们的性高潮次数。
interaction it is so a one night stand
一夜情，
you could probably guess this a one
你可能已经猜到了，
night stand or um uh a one night or
一夜情，或者，嗯，一夜情，或者
let's say a one night stand or casual
说一夜情或随意性
sex if you are secure or you are anxious
行为。如果你是安全型依恋，或者你是焦虑型依恋，
you despise that the the data showed
你讨厌那种行为，数据显示，获得
orgasms in one night stands or casual
性高潮的人的比例……
sex was substantially low if they were
如果对方是
uh if they were secure or anxious but if
安全型或焦虑型依恋，那么一夜情或随意性行为的发生率会显著降低；但如果
they were
是
avoidant off the charts why is because
回避型依恋，发生率则会高得惊人。这是因为
the avoidance were like oh man I don't
回避型依恋者会想：“哦，天哪，我不
like I don't want the the the emotional
喜欢，我不想要那种情感上的
connection to it right and I and I think
联系。”我认为
it's important to see okay well
理解
attachment Styles it does play into how
依恋类型很重要，它确实会影响
we interact and why but when you
我们的互动方式和原因。当你
understand who you are you could begin
了解自己时，你就可以开始
to to shift those
改变这些
patterns I'm sure a lot of people can
模式。我相信很多人都能
relate in various ways so you're saying
感同身受。所以你的意思是，如果
orgasm on a one night stand if you are a
你是
needy or a secure because you just won't
依赖型或安全型依恋，那么你在一夜情中达到性高潮的可能性要小得多，因为你
it won't be connecting with you you
无法与对方建立情感联系，
safe in that context absolutely just as
在这种情况下你无法获得心理上的安全感。就像
avoidant has less number of orgasms in a
回避型依恋者在“炮友”关系中达到性高潮的次数较少一样，这是
scenario why because you have to give up
因为在“炮友”关系中，回避型依恋者不得不放弃
some emotional intimacy as an avoidant
一些情感上的亲密感。
right and whereas secure would have a
而安全型依恋者在一夜情中的性高潮次数会
slightly higher than they would with
略高于一夜情。
with a one night stand so all of this is
所以，这一切最终都与此有关。
the day it's about really
今天，重要的是真正
knowing who you are and why you are
了解自己，了解自己为什么会这样，了解自己的
knowing attachment style knowing about
依恋类型，了解自己
your traumas in life knowing about your
人生中的创伤，了解自己的
triggers knowing about how you
触发点，了解自己的
communicate when you know all of these
沟通方式。当你了解所有
things you become a master of your
这些，你就能掌控自己的
environment Marcus Garvey from Jamaica
环境。牙买加的马库斯·加维
right would always say become the the
总是说，成为
person who becomes a master of self
自我掌控者，才能
becomes a master of their environment it
成为环境掌控者。一切都
always begins with self I've got to dig
始于自我。关于
deeper on this point of sex because it
性这一点，我需要深入探讨，因为它
made me ask the question question that
让我产生了一个疑问：
does that suggest avoidance in the
回避型依恋者在
bedroom will like a different type of
性方面是否与
sex to a anxious like an avoidant might
焦虑型依恋者有不同的偏好？比如，回避型依恋者可能更喜欢不那么
less intimate right if you know what I
亲密的性爱，对吧？
yeah but I think this is a topic I I
嗯，我在这里只是假设，但我认为这是一个我
need to study now I'm gonna do I think
需要研究的课题。我打算
seriously is I'm willing to bet that an
认真地做一项研究。我敢打赌，
avoidant definitely has different sexual
回避型依恋者的性
boundaries and different sexual
界限和性
interests than secure or anxious because
兴趣肯定与安全型或焦虑型依恋者不同，因为
ultimately what you know what what is
归根结底，
driving the avoidant is saying I don't
驱动回避型依恋者的是：我不
want the emotional intimacy that comes
想要性爱带来的情感亲密。
with this event so anything that's
所以任何
driving the emotional intimacy I prefer
影响情感亲密的因素，我都
not to have it right so
不太喜欢，对吧？所以
I would I would willing to better voice
我会更明确地表达，
like let's not really talk we don't need
比如“我们还是别谈了，我们不需要
to talk is it do we need to talk no we
谈，对吧？”或者“我们需要谈吗？”“不，我们
don't need to talk about no that's
不需要谈这个，不，那是
kissing no that's n let's not kiss
接吻，不，那不是，我们别接吻。”
whereas I I I would willing to bet a
而我敢打赌，
secure wants and needs
安全型人格想要和需要的是
that it's a good study and an anxious oh
一段美好的关系，而焦虑型人格，哦，
oh I mean even more so an anxious
我的意思是，焦虑型人格
probably needs two days of foreplay you
可能需要两天的性前戏，你
know before and avoidant just wants a
知道，而回避型人格只是想要一次
transaction just wants a transaction
交易，只是想要一次交易，对吧？
right let's make it official
让我们正式确定关系吧。
maybe that's part of the reason you know
也许这就是部分原因。你知道，
last time we spoke I was speaking about
上次我们谈话时，我谈到了
different sex languages the the way I
不同的性爱语言。我当时的
described it was figuring out that my
描述是，我发现我的
girlfriend was speaking Spanish and I
女朋友在卧室里说西班牙语，而我
was speaking like French in the bedroom
在卧室里说法语，
and we just needed to find a mutual
我们只需要找到一种共同的
language or I speak a little bit of
语言，或者我会说一点
French he speaks a little bit of Spanish
法语，他会说一点西班牙语，
whatever this is a metaphor for
等等。这是一种比喻，用来形容
different types of sort of sexual
不同的性
preference or fantasy or things that
偏好、性幻想或让
turn you on but maybe that goes to
你兴奋的事情。也许这可以
explain why so many couples are
解释为什么这么多情侣在性方面遇到
struggling in the bedroom because one of
困难。 卧室里之所以会有这种现象，是因为其中一个人
them wants a certain type of Sex and the
想要某种类型的性爱，而
other one's much more emotional sex yes
另一个人则更注重情感上的性爱。是的，
this is such an important
这是一个非常重要的
topic because I think when you can see
话题，因为我认为当你用
your partner through that lens it's no
这种视角看待你的伴侣时，就不会
longer oh my God can you believe it he
再觉得“我的天哪，你敢信吗？他
didn't even want to kiss me like he's a
甚至都不想吻我，他简直就是个
an [__] but what it could be is that
混蛋！”。但事实可能是，
he is severely avoidant this is what he
他有严重的回避型人格障碍，这是他
learned from his parents and these are
从父母那里学来的。这些
behaviors that can change so let's work
行为是可以改变的，所以我们来努力改善
on the behaviors like I I I rarely do we
这些行为。我们很少遇到
have bad people rarely yes we there's a
坏人，很少。是的，我们确实有一
whole cohort of of of the dark tetrad
大群“黑暗四人格”，
there there are bad people but most
其中确实有坏人，但大多数
people are good but simply have bad
人都是好人，只是
behaviors we can work on the behaviors
行为方式不好。我们可以努力改善这些行为，
or just different behaviors or different
或者说，改变不同的行为方式。是的，没错，没错，没错，不同的行为方式。
that's true different behaviors I'm
我
really just pondering this idea of these
真的在思考回避型人格障碍这个想法，
cuz I'm an avoidant and none of my
因为我自己就是一个回避型人格障碍患者，我的幻想，以及
fantasies none of the things that really
真正让我兴奋的事情，都不
turned me on involve like talking
涉及交谈之类的。
and and like you know that like the the
你知道，
things that you think of which is all
你想到的那些事，比如
about like emotional connection and all
情感联结之类的，
that St those aren't the things that I I
并不是我所
hold as like fantasies right those
认为的幻想，对吧？
aren't the things and I was thinking
不是那种东西。我一直在想，
about how our fantasies are derived from
我们的幻想
our much of our like trauma and our our
很大程度上来源于我们的创伤、成长经历、
our our upbringing and our disconnection
疏离感，以及……
and our you know if you were if you were
你知道，如果你
bullied in school I I see this a lot
在学校被欺负过……我经常看到这种情况。
actually I remember it just took flat my
我记得我突然
head flash back to when I was 18 and I
回想起18岁的时候，我
met a guy and one of his fantasies that
遇到一个男人，
he was very vocal about was because he
他很坦率地谈到他的一个幻想：因为他
he was powerless when he was younger he
小时候很
was powerless in school and so he liked
无力，在学校也很无力，所以他喜欢
using terminology in the bedroom I
在卧室里使用一些特定的词汇。我
remember him saying this to me that made
记得他跟我说过，这些词汇让
him feel empowered and I remember
他感觉自己很有力量。当时我觉得他真是个
thinking what a [__] weirdo like at
怪胎，
the time yeah because it seemed a little
因为
bit sadistic what he was saying but to
他说的话听起来有点虐待狂。但是
think that something that happens on the
想想看，发生在
playground can translate right to the
操场上的事情，竟然能直接转化到
bedroom when you're 35 years old and the
35岁的时候的卧室里，
thing that gives you an erection is
让你勃起的东西，这真是太
pretty pretty interesting it's worth
有趣了，值得思考。
some further inspection it it is I mean
进一步探究，我的意思是，我们
experiences at home as we grew up our
成长过程中在家里的经历，我们在
experiences on the playground our
操场上的经历，
experiences with our first lovers but
与初恋的经历，
even beyond that the experiences that
甚至更远，
our great grandparents
我们曾祖父母的经历——战争、
had the wars that they were in the
他们经历的大屠杀、
Holocaust that they were in the
他们参与的
transatlantic slave trade that they were
跨大西洋奴隶贸易，
a part of all of these
所有这些
intergenerational bits of trauma right
代际创伤，
all of these things shape how we show up
所有这些都塑造了我们，塑造了
it shapes who you are today it shapes
今天的你，也塑造了今天的
who who I am today and that's why we
我。这就是为什么我们
have to go back and understand this and
必须回溯过去，理解这一切。
when you can understand that you can
当你理解了这一点，你就能
more fully appreciate your partner you
更充分地欣赏你的伴侣。
know just like you're saying with your
就像你和
friend I think it it's it's it's so
朋友说的那样，我觉得这
great because you're saying okay when I
很棒，因为你说：“好吧，当我
heard this that was it sounded crazy
听到这些的时候，我觉得这简直是
talk but now I understand so we could
胡说八道，但现在我明白了。”所以我们可以
begin to dialogue about this you know
开始讨论这个问题。
and it's it's an interesting question
这是一个有趣的问题：
whether his fetish is wrong and it's
他的癖好是错误的，
needs fixing and it's like yuck or if
需要纠正，令人作呕，还是
it's just different
仅仅不同而已？嗯，
mhm and I guess that comes down to
我想这最终取决于它
whether it hurts anybody yeah guess
是否会伤害到别人。是的，我想
that's the key exactly filter exactly if
这才是关键所在。 没错，
if it hurts it's he he's he's in the
如果让他感到痛苦，那就是他，他属于施虐
sadist category uh and and that's
狂的范畴。嗯，这
something that should be
应该在
addressed chapter seven of your book is
你书的第七章里讨论，那就是“在
what to look for in a relationship yes
一段感情关系中应该寻找什么”。是的，
now I think this is a really really
我认为这是一个非常非常
important subject
重要的话题，
because this is often where many people
因为很多人常常在这方面
go wrong and I went many you I went
犯错，我也犯过很多很多
wrong for many many years by having this
年的错误，那就是
kind of list of superficial things we
列出一些肤浅的标准。我们
talked earlier about how
之前讨论过，
women are typically on average looking
女性通常平均会寻找与
academic level of qualification as them
自己
in various studies and there's multiple
在各个学科领域拥有相似学历的男性。
websites now where you can go on and
现在有很多网站可以让你
input what you're looking for and these
输入你想要寻找的条件，这些
websites tell you what chance you have
网站会告诉你找到理想伴侣的几率。
of finding that and I think much of the
我认为
purpose of these websites is just to
这些网站的主要目的就是为了
illuminate the fact that like it doesn't
说明一个事实：理想伴侣并不
exist upstairs before I came downstairs
存在。在我下楼之前，
late is I was sat upstairs with my
我和朋友坐在楼上，她正在
friend who's upstairs watching now big
楼上看
fan of yours and I asked them the
你的节目，她是你的忠实粉丝。我问了她一些
questions I said can you just tell me
问题，我说：“你们能告诉我
what you're looking for in a man okay
你们在寻找什么样的男人吗？”
of these websites asks it says these are
其中一个网站问了五个问题，上面写着：
the five questions okay do you want
五个问题，好的，你想要找
someone is married or not married person
已婚还是未婚的人？
upstairs said not married okay okay good
楼上的人说未婚，好的，好的，没问题。
check check what race do you want them
你理想中想要什么种族？
to be ideally and I told them to be
我让他们说
honest with me they said white I said
实话，他们说白人，我说，
okay I said get out
好的，我说，滚出去，
how dare you um so they said not married
你怎么敢？嗯，所以他们说未婚，
in white and I said how high and she
白人，我问多高，她
muled and she muled and she
嗯嗯嗯，嗯嗯嗯，她
M she was like that and then she said
就是那样，然后她说
ideally I mean 62 or 63 but you know I
理想身高，我的意思是6英尺2英寸或6英尺3英寸，但你知道，我
guess I should say and then she said 6
想我应该说，然后她说6
foot so I put in 6'2 okay and then I
英尺，所以我输入6英尺2英寸，好的，然后我
said and then the fourth question is
说，第四个问题是
obese or not obese she said not obese
肥胖还是不肥胖，她说不肥胖，
and I said what amount of money do you
我问你
want them to earn she came out with 150k
希望他们年收入多少，她说15万美元，对，听起来像
yeah right sounds in pounds in pounds so
英镑，对，英镑，所以
I converted that to dollars for this
我把它换算成美元，以便这个
website the last question that I asked
网站使用。我问的最后一个问题
was about the age range oh man right so
是关于年龄范围，哦，天哪，对，
what age range do you want the person to
你希望这个人多大年龄范围？
be and I believe she said yeah she said
我相信她说，对，她说
31 to 45 wow okay okay so that narrows
31到45岁，哇，好的，好的。 这
it down further and then using data from
进一步缩小了范围，然后利用美国人口普查局进行的
the 2020 annual social and economic
2020年年度社会和经济
supplement the E the
补充
ASC of the current population survey in
调查（ASC）的数据，
States this gives her a
她
0.046% chance of finding the person
找到目标的概率只有0.046%。
there you go how' she how'd she
你看，她当时的
respond it was like that same sound
反应是什么？听起来就像是那种“卧槽，
of [__] yeah but I but I think that's
太棒了！”的声音。但我认为这很
important because it go it leads into
重要，因为它引出了
what we're about to talk about which
我们接下来要讨论的内容：我们应该关注什么？
should we be looking for because listen
我们应该寻找什么？因为
if we're looking for someone that's You
如果我们寻找的是那种
Know Rich tall a certain race you know a
富有、高挑、特定种族、
certain waistline has a certain amount
特定腰围、
of money in the bank account and is not
银行账户里有一定数额存款、未婚，而且年龄在
30 plus we're really setting ourselves
30岁以上的人，那我们实际上
up for failure in many respects it's
在很多方面都注定要失败。这
really limiting us to a very small pool
实际上把我们的目标人群限制在一个非常小的范围内。
of individuals we we we are so what is
那么，
it that you need from all of my research
根据我
it has come down 10 years of research on
过去10年的研究，
this is I think there's five key
我认为
characteristics that we need one is you
我们需要哪些关键特征呢？首先，你
need a partner who's emotionally fit
需要…… 伴侣的情绪健康，
that's nowh on those questions I
这跟那些问题无关，我
guarantee you she's right now I saying
保证她现在说的是对的。我说，是的，
yes Paul I need emotionally fit I think
保罗，我需要一个情绪健康的伴侣。我觉得
she's going I need a
她会说，我需要
$250,000 no no I'm going to convince her
25万美元。不不，我要说服她，
on this emotional Fitness is far greater
情绪健康
than any amount of money and here's the
远比金钱重要。情绪
reason why emotional fit means that you
健康意味着你
are emotionally stable you are
情绪稳定，你情商很高。
emotionally intelligent but but let me
但是，让我来
talk about emotional stability this is
谈谈情绪稳定性，这一点
this is so important is that in
非常重要。在
relationships what I often hear people
人际关系中，我经常听到人们
not mention at all is something called
完全忽略一个叫做
Low
低
neuroticism that's being emotionally
神经质的概念，也就是情绪
stable now what is that that means that
稳定。那么，低神经质是什么意思呢？这意味着，
when your partner goes through a high or
当你的伴侣经历情绪高涨或
a low or you go through a high or a low
低落，或者你自己经历情绪高涨或低落时，
you still show up as the same person now
你仍然表现得和以前一样。
why is this important because life is
为什么这很重要？因为生活
filled with ups and downs constantly I
充满了起伏。我想说，
would say that the moment I knew my wife
我意识到我的妻子
was the one that I wanted to marry her
就是我想要娶的人的那一刻，是
was when my grandfather passed away it
我祖父去世的时候。那对我来说是一个
was a crushing blow I loved him dearly
沉重的打击，我非常爱他。
he passes away she dropped everything to
他去世后，她放下一切，
drive me eight hours she went she she
开车八个小时来接我。她真的去了，她真的去了，她竭尽全力
support me and she never
支持我，她从未……
changed her behaviors never changed she
她的行为并没有改变，她
was always the same loving person when
始终是那个充满爱心的人。
she lost her job she lost her job when
她失业的时候，我们正处于恋爱关系中，她失业了，但她
we were dating never Chang changed it
从未改变。这确实令人沮丧，
was it was demoralizing but she was
但她
still kind to me right and and and and
仍然对我很好。
so to have someone who's emotionally
所以，拥有一个情绪
stable who can go through the lows still
稳定、能够度过低谷并保持自我的人
remain themselves is incredibly
至关重要。
important so you need someone who's
你需要一个
emotionally fit that's one second is you
情绪健康的人，这是第一点。你
need someone who has courageous Vision
需要一个有勇气和远见的人，
right and and this speaks to Carol ri's
这符合卡罗尔·里提出的
six dimensions of psychological
心理健康六维度。
well-being you want someone who feels
你需要一个感觉
like they're on the path to something
自己走在人生道路上的人，
because if you don't feel like you're on
因为如果你感觉不到自己在前进的
the path to something you are stuck in
道路上，你就会陷入
mediocrity you are you you you don't
平庸，你
have any drive to get up in the morning
早上起床没有动力，
right or you you you you there's no
或者你
up in life so you need someone that has
在生活中缺乏自信。所以你需要一个对
a vision for themselves in in life so so
自己的人生有愿景的人，这
that's very important you know next you
非常重要。接下来，你
need someone who is I call it
需要一个我称之为“
resiliently resourceful very important
韧性资源型”的人，这在困境中非常重要。
resiliently resourceful they can bounce
韧性资源型的人能够迅速
back like yeah I'm going to be knocked
恢复。 没错，我肯定会被
down cuz you will be knocked down see
击倒，因为你也会被击倒。你看，
you must have been knocked down all the
你肯定经历过
time countless right but what do you do
无数次的挫折，对吧？但你会怎么做？
you get back up and you figure out a way
你会重新站起来，想办法把
how do I take all of these pieces that
这些破碎的碎片拼凑起来，重新
have been cracked and how do I create a
组成一幅
beautiful Mosaic out of those pieces
美丽的马赛克。这种韧性和
that's resilient resourcefulness
足智多谋
incredibly important then you need
非常重要。然后你需要一个
someone who's open-minded right open
思想开放的人，对吧？开放的
mind and understanding ultimately what
思想和理解。最终，这
does that mean that means curiosity and
意味着什么？这意味着好奇心。
I say this curi osity is one of the
我说好奇心是
sexiest traits in the world curiosity
世界上最性感的特质之一，
because if you have a partner who's
因为如果你有一个充满
curious what will they do they want to
好奇心的伴侣，他们会做什么？他们想
know everything about you they listen
了解你的一切，他们会倾听，他们会
they listen to you and they care about
关心他们
what they're hearing and that allows you
听到的内容，这会让你们之间建立起
to have strong emotional intimacy so
强烈的情感亲密关系，所以这一点
that's very important and then last is
非常重要。最后，
you need someone who's going to give you
你需要一个能给你充满
compassionate support someone who's
同情心的支持的人，一个会在你跌倒时陪伴在
going to be there for you you know when
你身边的人。你知道，当
you get knocked down I'm right here for
你跌倒时，我会一直陪在
you if you have these these traits you
你身边。如果你具备这些特质，你就具备了成为
partner for you and that person doesn't
你最强大伴侣的潜质，而这个人不需要
have to test highly in all those
考验你。 在所有这些
categories they just simply need to be
方面都很优秀的人，只需要
on the pathway to realizing those
走上实现这些目标的道路即可。
because if you have someone who embodies
因为如果你遇到一个具备
those characteristics you have someone
这些特质的人，你就找到了一个
who could resolve conflict with you but
可以帮你解决冲突的人。但是，人们
about online dating and dating apps
对网上约会和约会软件的看法又如何呢？
because there's no dating app that helps
因为没有哪个约会软件能真正展现
focus and kindness and empathy that you
你所说的那些品质：情感健康、勇敢的远见、坚韧的智慧、足智多谋、开放的心态、同情心、支持、专注、善良和同理心。
talk about there's no dating apps that
没有哪个约会软件会把这些
put that front and center I have to make
放在首位。我必须
a decision on these dating apps within
在0.1秒内对这些约会软件做出决定，
0.1 seconds just based on you know does
仅仅基于
their face look like Paul
他们的脸长得像保罗·
brunson's do they have shoulders like
布伦森吗？他们的肩膀像
shet yeah but I mean so it feels like
什么？是的，我的意思是，感觉
every time I come now I'm pitching you a
每次我来这里，向你推销
dating app we should we should do
约会软件的时候，我们都应该……我们应该……
though that's the truth yeah see this is
但是没有人会下载这个约会软件，这是事实。 这就是
why I've written this book right what
我写这本书的原因，对吧？
I'm saying here is that is attraction
我想说的是，吸引力很
important yeah it's still important I I
重要，它仍然很重要。
I say that there's five fundamentals but
我说过有五个基本要素，但
then there's also some Dynamics we need
除此之外，还有一些动力因素也很重要。
we need to make sure that we're
我们需要确保我们
physically attracted to the person we
对对方有生理上的吸引力，我们
need to have the same relationship goals
需要有相同的恋爱目标，
that's important we need to make sure
这很重要。我们需要确保
that um you know we can resolve conflict
我们能够共同解决冲突。
together all of these pieces are
所有这些因素都很
important but what I'm telling telling
重要，但我告诉
you is without question these five
你的是，毫无疑问，这五个
fundamentals are the most important now
基本要素是最重要的。
I believe that as our needs change the
我相信，随着我们需求的变化，
technology will adapt to how our needs
技术也会随之
change think about gen Z for example
改变。想想Z世代，比如
jenz is saying physical attraction is
Jenz，他说生理吸引力很
important but my willingness and desire
重要，但真诚的意愿和渴望
to be authentic is even more important
更重要。
so already we're changing even on Tinder
所以我们已经在改变了，即使在Tinder上，
we're changing we're allowing more
我们也在改变，我们允许
for people to disclose more and more
人们更多地透露
about themselves so I think that the
自己的信息。所以我认为，
technology will change as we depict our
随着我们对自身需求的描述发生变化，技术也会随之改变。
needs to change as our needs change in
在
your book chapter eight you talk about
你的书的第八章，你谈到了
this and you said the word earlier the
这一点，你之前提到了“
dark tetrad yes dark
黑暗四人格”这个词。是的，黑暗
tetrad
四人格，
narcissists they exhibit attractive
自恋者，他们
qualities at the beginning of a
在开始时会表现出一些有吸引力的特质。 一段
relationship right because that's
关系中，自信是关键，因为这种
characterized by being sort of self
自信的特点是
assured like on the surface it seems
表面上看起来很
like confidence yes you know yes there's
自信。是的，你知道，
some great research around speed dating
关于快速约会有很多很棒的研究，
and it looked at who are the most
研究了哪些人在
successful when it comes to speed dating
快速约会中最成功。
and you know who the most successful are
你知道，最成功的是
two types of people narcissists and
两种人：自恋者和
Psychopaths they're the most successful
精神病患者。他们
at speed dating now why is it the truth
在快速约会中最成功。为什么呢？正如
what you were just saying they show up
你刚才所说，他们表面上看起来很
as self- assured as confident but you
自信，很自负，但你
know what else they do they're willing
知道他们还会做什么吗？他们会
to lie they're willing to tell you
撒谎，会说
anything you want to hear to get what
任何你想听的话来达到目的，
they want because that's their objective
因为这就是他们的目的。他们的
their objective is to use you like this
目的是利用你，就像利用这
cup of of of water right here when I'm
杯水一样。当我
done drinking this water the cup is gone
喝完这杯水后，杯子就没了，
I don't need it anymore that's how a
我不再需要它了。这就是
narcissist or a psychopath shows up and
自恋者或精神病患者的表现方式，
so that's the reason why they're they're
所以这就是
they're Ultra successful is there a
他们非常成功的原因。是否存在某种
certain type of person that's more prone
类型的人更容易被自恋
to be attracted to narcissists yes I
者吸引？是的，我是
mean Psychopaths yeah they're definitely
指精神病患者。是的，他们肯定存在。 确实存在一些
there there's there's there's different
不同的
personality types that enable themselves
人格类型，他们会让自己更容易接近
to a to anyone in the dark tetrad but in
黑暗四人格中的任何人，但
essence what it is is in essence it's
本质上，这指的是
going to be someone who is not secure
缺乏安全感
and it's going to be someone who has low
和低
self-esteem because when you have low
自尊的人。因为低
self-esteem you're seeking that
自尊的人会寻求
validation you're seeking their
认可，寻求他人的肯定和肯定，而他们
and the more that they distance
越是疏远你，你就越
from you the more you want their
渴望得到他们的
affirmation they probably see you as an
肯定。他们可能还会把你当成一个
easy Tona as well they beam right into
容易得手的对象，直接接近
you and they destroy your life they
你，然后毁掉你的
destroy your life I I I think that the
生活。我认为“
term narcissism or narcissist is one of
自恋”或“自恋者”这个词被
the most overused words probably like in
滥用了，就像在
modern-day dating everyone is a
现代约会中，每个人都被认为是
narcissist but everyone is not a
自恋者，但并非每个人都是
narcissist they're just a bit selfish
自恋者，他们只是有点自私，有点混蛋，有点傲慢。有些人确实
people have narcissistic traits but when
有自恋的特征，但当
you're talking about a clinically
你谈论的是临床
diagnosed narcissist that is an
诊断的自恋者时，情况就完全不同了。 自恋者是
extremely dangerous person how many
非常危险的人。你提到的“
people are within this dark tetrad that
黑暗四人格”中，有多少人属于这一类？“
you talk about and the dark tetrad is
黑暗四人格”指的是
narcissism psychopathy machiavellism and
自恋、精神病态、马基雅维利主义和
sadism right and sadism absolutely so
虐待狂，没错，虐待狂绝对是其中之一。这
those those four make up the dark tetrad
四种特质构成了“黑暗四人格”。
and on average the estimate is less than
据估计，平均而言，只有不到
15 15% so less than 15% of the
15%的
population fall within one of those
人属于这一
categories now it's important to say
类。需要强调的是，
that that category extremely dangerous
这一类人极其危险，因为
to the point where a narcissist once a
一旦成为​​自恋者，就
narcissist always a
永远是
narcissist and so the question always to
自恋者。所以，我经常被问到的问题
me is well Paul I found out that my my
是：保罗，我发现我的
partner is is a
伴侣是
narcissist what do I do well I
自恋者，我该怎么办？我的
say if you want to remain in a Rel
回答是，如果你想继续
relationship with someone that is going
和那种会
to continually use you and may learn to
不断利用你、或许会学会
manage their behavior but will always
控制自己的行为，但始终把
see you as an object to
你视为
use than stay in the relationship but
利用对象的人维持一段关系，那就继续下去；
otherwise you have to leave what one of
否则，你必须离开。
my friends is one of the top experts on
我的一个朋友是世界上顶尖的自恋专家之一，
narcissism in the world and when I sit
每次我坐下来和他谈话时，
down I always say are you sure you can't
我都会问他：你确定吗？
change if you're a narcissist like I
如果你像我
just met he's a great guy like she she
刚认识的那个人一样是个自恋者，那你没办法改变他。他是个很棒的人，就像她一样，
she she without question you cannot and
毫无疑问，你不可能改变他。她专门和
narcissists and tells me how she's able
自恋者一起工作，告诉我她是如何
to teach them how to just manage what it
教他们如何控制自己的行为的。
is that they do but if you are someone
但如果你
and and and your partner is and I'm not
和你的伴侣是自恋者，我说的不是
talking about they have narcissistic
他们有自恋的
traits you know arrogant Etc I'm talking
特质，比如傲慢等等，而是
about they have they've been clinically
他们被临床
diagnosed as a narcissist you are in for
诊断为自恋型人格障碍，那么和他们在一起，你的
an extremely extremely hard life with
生活将会极其艰难。
them how' you spot an Nar nist oh my God
如何识别自恋者呢？我的天哪，
I me you know so people talk about love
你知道，人们总是谈论“爱的
bombing all the time but but but
轰炸”，但
ultimately a narcissist objective is to
归根结底，自恋者的目标是
use you for whatever it is like to use
利用你，
you use you use you for for their
利用你来满足他们的
pleasure they could have some
欲望。他们可能还带有一些
machiavellianism mixed in because a lot
马基雅维利主义的成分，因为
of the dark tetrad the characteristics
黑暗四人格的很多特征都有
overlap where machiavellianism is about
重叠之处，而马基雅维利主义指的是为了满足
strategy specific specifically for their
自身欲望而采取的特定策略。
pleasure so the key is to look at their
所以关键在于观察他们的
behavior and to look at their behavior
行为，观察他们的…… 长时间的行为观察，虽然令人
where it gets fatiguing but important so
疲惫，但却至关重要。
the studies show that when you are in a
研究表明，如果你处于一段
committed
稳定的恋爱
relationship committed for two years on
关系中，
average and then you get married the
平均持续两年，然后结婚，
divorce rate is substantially lower
离婚率会显著降低。
right we found that the divorce rate is
我们发现，现在的离婚率只有
20 22% now now why is that it's because
20%到22%。为什么会这样呢？因为
you've had the opportunity to see your
你有机会见证
partner in the ups and downs in the
伴侣的起起落落，感受他们的
low neuroticism can they bounce back to
喜怒哀乐，看看他们是否神经质，能否迅速恢复，以及他们是否在
see are they using you for whatever
利用你达到某种
their purposes are the challenge is a
目的。问题在于，
lot of us see the behavior and decide to
我们很多人看到这些行为后，仍然选择
stay you know why we decide to stay
留下。你知道我们为什么选择留下吗？
because that list that
因为那张清单——
you he makes over 100,000 he's over over
他列出了超过10万条记录，他身高超过
6 feet he's this he's that he checks
6英尺，他拥有这个，他拥有那个——符合
these boxes that mean nothing to my
这些条件，但这些对我的
happiness truly means nothing to your
幸福毫无意义，对你来说也毫无意义。
happiness it means something to the
它对
validation that you're getting from the
你从
public but to your actual well-being
公众那里获得的认可或许有意义，但对你的实际幸福而言，它微不足道，
nothing but they check those boxes so
毫无价值。但他们符合这些条件，
therefore I'm going to stay and you're
所以，我会留下，你也会
going to stay and this is what you're
留下。这就是…… 你
going to get when you stay you're going
留下来之后会怎样？你会
to live under duress you're going to
生活在压力之下，你会
feel lonely you're going to feel
感到孤独，你会感到
isolated your cortisol levels are going
孤立，你的皮质醇水平会
to go up you're going to get
升高，你会出现
inflammation you're more susceptible to
炎症，你会更容易
disease you're going to die early you
生病，你会早逝，你会很
are going to be miserable why it's
痛苦。
interesting when you're talking about
当你谈到
understanding their relationship history
了解他们的恋爱史时，这很有意思，
because a narcissist wouldn't tell you
因为自恋者不会告诉你。
but then it got me thinking about this
但这让我想到了
idea of like cheating and infidelity and
出轨、不忠和
betrayal in previous relationships and I
背叛这些行为。我
wanted to ask you this random question
想问你一个随机的问题：
which is if you find out your partner
如果你发现你的伴侣
has previously cheated another
以前出轨过，这算不算一个
relationships is that a red flag I mean
危险信号？我的意思是，
I don't necessarily necessarily uh
我并不一定完全
ascribe to Red hard fast like because I
认同“黑暗四人格”的说法，因为我
believe that behavior can be can can can
相信行为是可以
can can change so is anything a red flag
改变的。
other than this dark
除了“黑暗
tetrad no nothing's a red flag there's
四人格”之外，还有什么算是危险信号吗？没有，没有什么算是危险信号，根本
no such thing I think the dark tetrad is
没有这种东西。我认为“黑暗四人格”
is the red flag and no effort is the red
才是危险信号，而毫无努力才是危险
flag if criminal history at all I I you
信号，如果还有犯罪记录的话。你
know this is this interesting I have
知道，这很有意思，我有
plenty of family members who have been
很多这样的家人。 我认识一些被
incarcerated and who are some of the
监禁过的成员，他们是我
best people in the world I've met a lot
见过的世界上最好的人之一。
of them actually a lot of incarcerated
实际上，我认识很多这样的人，很多被监禁过的
people that are morally better more
人，他们的道德品质比
sound than anybody I know than anybody I
我认识的任何人都高尚、健全。
know I would trust them with my to to to
我甚至愿意把我的
with my child you know um I think no
孩子托付给他们。你知道，嗯，我觉得
effort is a red flag when you have a
如果你的
partner who says n that therap I'm not
伴侣说“治疗，我不会那样
going to do that what watch a a video on
做”，或者“去看个关于
active listening I'm not going to do
积极倾听的视频，我不会那样做”，或者“
that uh what you're talking about we
你在说什么？我们
need to do a trust exercise no no I'm
需要做一个信任练习”，或者“不不，我
not that is a red flag the dark tetrad
不会”，这都是危险信号。黑暗四人格，
those are red flags I can't think of any
这些都是危险信号。我想不出
others I had a really random question I
其他的了。我还有一个很随意的问题
wanted to ask you as well which is um if
想问你，那就是，如果
you don't want to do something in a
你在一段关系中不想做某件事，
relationship it kind of leads to what
这有点像
you were just saying there if you don't
你刚才说的，如果你不想
want to do
做
something should you tell your partner
某件事，你应该告诉你的伴侣吗？
so your wife goes to you hey Paul I want
比如你妻子对你说：“嘿，保罗，我想
to go watch this ballet thing um do you
去看芭蕾舞表演，你
want to come mhm in that moment you have
想一起去吗？”嗯，在那一刻，你根本
no desire to go and watch the ballet yes
不想去。 去看芭蕾舞？对，对，该
right how how does one respond are you
怎么回答？你是替
asking for for a friend for a friend
朋友问的吗？替朋友问的？对，替
yeah for a friend oh my God all right no
朋友问的。哦，我的天哪，好吧，不是。
because like something I've been
因为我
thinking about a lot lately which is
最近一直在想一件事，
like me and my partner have talked about
我和我的伴侣也讨论过
it a lot which
很多次，那就是
is if I ask her if she wants to do
如果我问她想不想做
something
某件事，
she tell me the truth and go no I don't
她应该告诉我实话，说“不，我
want to go watch Manchester United play
不想去看曼联的比赛”吗？
or should she should just come along and
还是她应该陪我一起去？
do it CU she should be helping me meet
她应该帮我满足
my needs yeah all right to answer that
我的需求。好吧，要回答这个
question it's really about your history
问题，这实际上取决于你们过去
in resolving conflict and have you been
解决冲突的经验，以及你们
able to resolve conflict as a
作为
partnership in a healthy way because
伴侣是否能够以健康的方式解决冲突。因为
what we what ends up happening in
我们在
relationships is let's say before she
恋爱关系中经常会遇到的情况是，比如说，在她
asked you about Manchester United right
问你关于曼联的事之前，
you've had a disagreement but the
你们有过分歧，但
disagreement was not resolved and
分歧没有解决，她感到很受伤，你也感到很受伤。那么
side well she's going to learn and it
她就会学会
with you because she knows that you as a
对你不诚实，而且这种做法会得到强化，因为她知道你们作为
couple have an inability to resolve
伴侣无法解决
conflict and therefore she wants to
冲突，因此她想要
protect herself and often times what
保护自己。而
ends up happening in relationships is
恋爱关系中经常会发生的事情是……
that
那些
patterns toxic behaviors patterns are
有毒的行为模式会
reinforced time and time and time again
一次又一次地被强化，
so you get to a point where of course
所以最终你们当然
you can't tell each other the truth
无法对彼此坦诚相待，
because the moment that you do it's it's
因为一旦坦白，就会
a it's a it's there's an explosion
爆发。
that's why it's important you have to
这就是为什么
build a great relationship is just like
建立良好的关系如此重要。就像在
layer on top of a layer on top of a
一张
layer very thin a piece of paper and
很薄的纸上一层又一层地叠加一样，每次你们
something good as a partnership every
作为伴侣共同做出好事，
time you affirm your partner she affirms
每次你肯定你的伴侣，她肯定
you you resolve conflict whatever it may
你，你们解决冲突，无论
be it's another layer that's added to to
是什么，都会为这段关系增添一层新的厚实。
to that partnership and as you're
随着你们的
growing and you're growing it affords
成长，你们有机会
you the opportunity to be more bluntly
更加
transparent to the point where I walk
坦诚直率，甚至到了我
out my wife's like why you have those
走出家门时会问我妻子：“你为什么穿那条
leather trousers on like those are
皮裤？太滑稽了！”我们已经到了可以非常坦率地、无比真诚地对待
ridiculously authentic with each other
彼此的地步，这
and it's because we have Stacks and
是因为我们积累了无数的宝贵经验。 因为你们
stacks and Stacks and stacks of previous
之前的关系
Foundation of History so I can't
基础很深，所以我不能
immediately say
立刻说要你
walk out and be ultra transparent
彻底坦诚，
because I don't know what the history is
因为我不知道你们的关系历史。
but if you have a strong history and
但是，如果你有良好的关系基础，并且
you're able to resolve conflict in a
能够以
healthy way then you are able to be even
健康的方式解决冲突，那么你就能
more transparent it's you know
更加坦诚。你知道，
relationships are this constant balance
人际关系是一种持续的平衡，需要不断地
of checking in understanding your
了解
partner's feelings affirming what those
伴侣的感受，肯定他们的感受，
feelings are understanding your desires
理解自己的需求和感受，
what your feelings are ensuring that
确保这些需求得到肯定。这是一个持续的过程，
there are affirmed it's constant it's
它一直在
constantly moving which is why I always
发展变化。这就是为什么我总是
say it's like the the the marriage
说，就像婚姻一样，在
partnership you're never just this
伴侣关系中永远不会停滞不前。你永远不会只是这样，要么关系在
you're either growing or the
成长，要么关系在消亡，
no in between [__] there's no in between
没有中间状态。
but it sounds like it's growing sounds
听起来
like yours is growing I know it is
你们的关系正在成长，我知道它正在
growing it is growing because do you
成长，因为你
know why it's growing because of the
知道它为什么在成长吗？因为
thing you said earlier which is because
你之前说过，是因为
of effort and because both parties care
双方都愿意
to put in the effort so there must be so
付出努力。所以肯定有
many people I would Hazard a guess that
很多人，我猜
the majority of people are the 80% that
大多数人就像
you described earlier you said there's
你之前描述的那80%一样。 有人说，有
20% that are happier than ever and 80%
20%的人比以往任何时候都更快乐，80%的人
that are less satisfied than ever I
比以往任何时候都更不满意。我
would Hazard a guess that there's an 80%
敢打赌，现在有80%
of listeners out there now that are in a
的听众都身处一段
relationship where they realize that the
关系中，他们意识到彼此的
effort is gone and it went they don't
付出已经消失殆尽。他们不
know when it went maybe it was when they
知道这种付出是什么时候消失的，也许是在
had kids and work became really really
有了孩子、工作变得异常
busy but at some point along the way
忙碌之后，但总之，在某个时刻，
effort became de prior ized yeah and
付出被置于次要地位。是的，他们曾经
there was a belief
认为，即使
without nutrients and water and sunlight
没有养分、水和阳光，一切也会保持不变。
yes you know what I mean but there's no
是的，你明白我的意思。但是，
nothing in nature can grow without
自然界中没有任何东西可以脱离
continual nourishment of some form so
某种形式的持续滋养而生长。那么，
chapter nine my last question
第九章，我的最后一个问题。
okay in chapter nine of your book you
好的，在你的书的第九章中，你
talk about John godman's Four Horsemen
谈到了约翰·戈德曼的“四骑士”。是的，
yes what are the four horsemen Okay so
什么是“四骑士”？
John gotman phenomenal I'd say one of
约翰·戈德曼是一位杰出的人物，可以说是研究婚姻维系之道的
the top researchers on what it takes for
顶尖学者之一。
a marriage to sustain itself and he
他
analyzed hundreds and hundreds and
分析了成百上千对
hundreds of of of couples and he
夫妇，甚至将
actually would break them down into six
他们的互动分解成六
second increments because he would he
秒钟的片段，因为他会
would he would videotape them and he
拍摄他们的视频，
would look at how they interact with
观察他们
with each other and he determined that
彼此之间的互动。 他还发现，
based on how they interact with each
伴侣之间的互动方式可以
other is in indicative of if they will
预示他们是否会
stay together in a relationship and he
继续维持这段关系。他
identified these
总结了四种
four types of interaction that suggest
互动模式，这些模式表明他们的关系可能存在问题。
and one of the four he if he sees with
如果出现其中一种，他有
99% accuracy he believes they will break
99%的把握认为他们会分手。这四种模式是什么呢？第一种是
criticism one is
批评，第二种是
defensiveness a third is stonewalling
防御，第三种是冷战。
but here's the biggest and I see this a
但最主要的，也是我经常看到的，是
contempt if you have a partner who shows
蔑视。如果你的伴侣对
you contempt as Dr gotman would say
你表现出蔑视，正如戈特曼博士所说，
there's a 99% likelihood you you'll
你们分手的可能性高达99%。
break up as a couple now why is that the
为什么呢？
reason why is because real contempt
因为真正的蔑视
suggests that you are on a whole another
表明你和
level than your partner it's a level of
你的伴侣完全不在一个层次上，这是一种不
disrespect you're saying to your partner
尊重，你是在告诉你的伴侣：
you're no longer on my level and you can
你不再和我处于同一水平。
seek contempt show up in these small
蔑视可能以短短
six-second increments you you're
六秒钟的形式出现。当你
watching a couple you know I see it all
观察一对情侣时，我经常看到这种情况。
the time I see couples um arguing and
我看到情侣争吵，你会
you see the eye roll the Look Away the
看到他们翻白眼，眼神交流。 回头
look back in just those moments One
看看那些时刻，你会发现
partner is saying you're not even on my
伴侣在说“你根本不配和我
level like you shouldn't even be my
相提并论，你甚至不配出现在我的生活中”。
presence right when you see that level
当你感受到
of disrespect coming from your partner
伴侣如此不尊重你时，
you know they don't they don't respect
你就知道他们不
you they don't value you and so the the
尊重你，不重视你。所以，
the Four Horsemen of of the Apocalypse
末日四骑士是
is is is real and it's something that we
真实存在的，我们
need to be aware of because when we're
需要意识到这一点。因为当我们
aware of these things we we we can
意识到这些事情时，我们就能
witness are they showing up with our
观察它们是否出现在我们的
partner or are they showing up with us
伴侣身上，或者是否出现在我们自己身上。
where does that contempt start what is
这种轻蔑从何而来？是什么
the seed that grows into contempt it it
种子长成了轻蔑？它
it could it could start from a myriad of
可能来自很多
places you know I fundamentally believe
方面。我从根本上相信，
it begins with us selecting bad Partners
它始于我们选择了糟糕的伴侣。
you know it begins with us choosing a
它始于我们选择了一个
partner that we have very little hope of
几乎没有希望与他
completing the Finish Line with you know
走到最后的人。你明白我的
what I mean and so we are not on the
意思吗？所以我们在
same page in terms of our relationship
关系
goals maybe we don't share the same
目标上不一致，也许我们没有相同的
values um you know our partners not kind
价值观，我们的伴侣
to us we can't resolve conflict and then
对我们不友善，我们无法解决冲突，然后
every small
每一次小小的
interaction there's another hairline
互动都会引发新的矛盾。
fracture another hairline fracture
裂痕，又一道细小的裂痕，
another hairline fracture and it grows
再一道细小的裂痕，就这样不断
don't break up because of one incident
扩大。大多数关系的破裂并非源于一次事件，而是因为
the course of time and you get to a
日积月累的数百次小摩擦，最终导致
point where you cannot take it anymore
你无法忍受。这就是
that's how most relationships break up
大多数关系破裂的原因。
so how do we stop those small incidents
那么，我们该如何阻止这些小摩擦
then compounding into a divorce is it is
累积成离婚呢？关键在于
it about conflict resolution oh yeah the
冲突解决吗？没错。
the top reason why most researchers will
大多数研究人员
say that we break up or we divorce is
认为，导致分手或离婚的主要原因是
they'll point to finance or they'll say
财务问题或婚外情等等。
infidelity or they but really what it is
但对
to me what I believe it is is it's our
我来说，真正的原因在于我们
inability to resolve the conflict about
无法解决
those topics so so so conflict
这些问题上的冲突。因此，冲突
resolution becomes one of the
解决成为维系一段
key drivers towards a highly satisfied
高度满意关系的关键驱动因素之一。
relationship but it begins before that
但这要从更早开始，始于
it begins with us reflecting on us doing
我们反思自身，做一些“
the woow woo work and saying am I happy
高深”的事情，问问自己：我快乐吗？
like when I wake up do I wake up with a
比如，我醒来时
smile on my face when I go to sleep like
脸上带着微笑吗？我入睡时感到
am I content am I happy with where I am
满足吗？我对目前的
at life do I do I feel like you know I'm
生活状态感到满意吗？我是否觉得自己
not where I want to be but but do I feel
还没达到理想状态？
like I'm on the pathway if you're
如果你对
answering yes to those things you are in
这些问题的回答都是“是”，那么你就走在正确的道路上，你处于
a place of satisfaction which means that
一种满足的状态，这
your light is on which means that I
意味着你的内心之光已经点亮。我
guarantee you the people in your life
保证，你生命中的人也同样如此。
their light is on you're meeting more
你会遇到更多的
people you're interacting with greater
人，与更优秀的
people you have a greater ability to
人互动，你更有能力
meet new people meet people who share
结识新朋友，遇到与你
those same desires and their light is on
志同道合、内心同样充满热情的人。
if your light is not on and you're
如果你内心没有热情，只是机械地
checking boxes then you're most likely
勾选选项，那么你很可能会
going to meet someone and their light
遇到一些人，他们的内心之光也
won't be on but they're checking boxes
不会点亮，但他们同样在勾选选项。
so you're already starting in a place
所以，你们
where your relationship is doomed to
的关系从一开始就注定
fail Cheryl Samberg 2014 her book uh
失败。谢丽尔·萨姆伯格在2014年
leanin when she wrote that book it blew
出版的《向着自信》（Leanin'）一书中，她写道，
choose as a partner is the most
选择伴侣是你
important career decision you could make
职业生涯中最重要的决定。这本书让我深受震撼，因为她说，选择伴侣是你职业生涯中最重要的决定。
then a couple years later Warren Buffett
几年后，沃伦·巴菲特在
comes out in his uh documentary and he
他的纪录片中也
says who you choose as a partner is the
提到，选择伴侣是
most important decision you could make
你职业生涯中最重要的决定。
and when I heard that I thought to
当我听到这句话时，我
myself W this this is interesting
心想：这很有意思，
because I was seated in finance and I
因为我当时在金融行业工作，我
thought it was about my network and
以为这只是…… 我的人脉、
education and who you know but really as
教育背景以及人脉关系固然重要，但当
I began to look at the people who were
我开始观察
the most satisfied in my life it was
生活中那些最满意的人时，我发现他们总是
always the people who had the strongest
拥有最牢固的
Intimate
亲密
Relationships Paul we have a closing
关系。保罗，我们
tradition on this podcast where the last
这个播客有个传统，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位
guest the question left for you
嘉宾留个问题。留给你的问题
is what things are you doing that are
是：你正在做的哪些事情让
contributing to keeping you stuck or
你停滞不前，或者
stopping you from progressing in the way
阻碍你按照
that you would like oh
自己想要的方式前进？哦，
wow I I still fight with feeling that I
哇，我仍然在与这种感觉作斗争，我
I feel like I'm the
感觉自己总是处于
underdog all the
劣势，
time and I think there's so many things
我觉得我过度分析了很多
overanalyze that I shouldn't be but I
不应该过度分析的事情。
I'll I'll give you an example and this
我给你举个例子，
is this is uh this is real and and I
这是真的，我
know people can empathize with this is
知道很多人都能感同身受。
you know sometimes I'll I'll talk to
有时候我会和
someone and I'll say you know are are
别人聊天，我会问他们：“
you responding to me that way because
你这样对我，是因为
I'm a black man is that why are you
我是黑人吗？是因为
responding to me that way because I'm
我是
American are you responding to me that
美国人吗？还是因为我
way because I'm whatever you see me on
是……不管你在电视上看到的是什么，我总是这样对我？” 我总是反复
always second guessing what I'm hearing
琢磨我听到的话，
and I think it's because I view myself
我觉得是因为我把自己看作一个
as this Underdog maybe not worthy not
弱者，也许不够优秀，不够强大，所以
enough that I am overanalyzing
我才会过度分析。
the positive is that it gives me extra
积极的一面是，这给了我额外的
drive and extra assert and extra I'm
动力和自信，让我更加坚定要全力以赴。
overthinking it but I think all of this
但消极的一面是，我觉得我给自己制造了障碍和阻碍。也许他们只是好奇才问我这个问题，
it as chess you know and I want to think
你知道，也许他们是真的感兴趣，所以才问的。也许我…… ... 你
written a unbelievably great book and
写了一本非常棒的书，
Timeless of this book and the um the
这本书不仅通俗易懂，而且经久不衰。书中蕴含的
wisdom that is PED into all of these
智慧，
Pages both qualitative and quantitative
无论是定性研究还是定量
research over you know the the amount of
研究，都令人叹为观止。书中引用了许多
incredible people that I know of that I
我认识的杰出人物，我
dream of having on this podcast one day
梦想有一天能邀请他们来我的播客节目做客。
that you've cited in your work in this
这
of the book you have some actionable
本书的结尾部分还提供了一些切实可行的
elements with this um yes wonderful
建议，帮助你建立美好的
long-term relationship satisfaction
长期关系。 是的，
scale yes which means that you can turn
这说明你可以把今天播客
all the wisdom that you've heard on this
里听到的所有智慧，
podcast today but also all the book all
以及这本书里的所有
the wisdom in these pages into something
智慧，都转化为
actionable and this book is really
可操作的行动。这本书真的很有
actionable that's one of the amazing
实用性，这也是它最棒的地方之一。
things about it you learn and you and
你会学到很多东西，
you know you go right back through the
你会回顾
research and the history of humans and
人类、
technology and Match.com and all of
科技、Match.com等等
those amazing things but you're left
这些精彩内容的研究和历史，但最终你会得到一些
with actionable advice on how to make
切实可行的建议，教你如何
changes in your life um and key
改变生活。正如
takeaways as we see at the end of the
我们在每章结尾看到的那样，这
chapters what a wonderful timely book
本书真是太棒了，它非常及时，也非常
what an important one because as often
重要，因为人们常说，
is said the quality of Our Lives can be
我们生活的质量
determined by the quality of our
取决于我们人际关系的质量，
relationships and this is exactly what
而这正是
this book Endeavors to do and does so
这本书努力的方向，而且它做得非常
well yes so thank you Paul for gracing
出色。所以，保罗，再次感谢你做客
our our show Once once again it's always
我们的节目，这始终是我的
an honor I could speak to you for
荣幸。我可以和你聊上几个
[__] hours so we're gonna have to do
小时，所以我们以后一定要再聊一次。
this again sometime but I I I deep I
我
deeply appreciate it is an honor to to
非常感激能来到
be here and uh love the conversation
这里，我很喜欢这次的对话，
thank
谢谢。
next we've discovered that people who
接下来，你需要一个播客来听吗？我们发现……
liked this episode also tend to
喜欢这期节目的人通常也很
absolutely love another recent episode
喜欢我们最近制作的另一期节目，
we've done so I've linked that episode
所以我把那期节目的链接放在
in the description below I know you'll
下面的描述里了，我知道你们会
enjoy it
喜欢的。
[Music]
[音乐]